<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Voracious Bookworm]]></title><description><![CDATA[writings about devoured books]]></description><link>https://voracious-bookworm.com</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Jun 2018 16:04:08 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[Reading Roundup 15]]></title><description><![CDATA[Keeping up the pace this week despite being distracted by re-reading a couple of my cheesy old YA favourites from high school ( Just Listen…]]></description><link>https://voracious-bookworm.com/reading-roundup-15/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://voracious-bookworm.com/reading-roundup-15/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 17 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Keeping up the pace this week despite being distracted by re-reading a couple of my cheesy old YA favourites from high school (&lt;em&gt;Just Listen&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;This Lullaby&lt;/em&gt; by Sarah Dessen)!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Daughter of the Pirate King&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;#x26; &lt;strong&gt;Daughter of the Siren Queen&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Popsugar Reading Challenge: Set at sea&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Goodreads Summer Reading Challenge: Ocean Blue&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This pair of YA books were a delightful jaunt into the world of pirates and sirens. The might have been my favourites if I’d read them in high school, but alas, they were a bit repetitive and shallow for me now. As a recommendation for YA readers for strong women and adventure, definitely. Maybe even an easy beach read.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Joy Luck Club&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Goodreads Summer Reading Challenge: School’s Out for Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last time I read this book was about ten years ago. I’d like to find the essay I wrote about it. The power of re-reading is in the reflection of how you’ve changed, and I’m sure I’d gain some insight by reading my old opinions. (I wonder what kinds of insight I’ll have reading back on this blog!?)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The style of multiple viewpoints over time seems like a theme in the Asian women authors I’ve read (&lt;em&gt;That Summer in Provincetown&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Ru&lt;/em&gt;). I feel like I’m getting a “2-for-1” kind of deal in terms of perspective. In &lt;em&gt;The Joy Luck Club&lt;/em&gt;, it’s eight stories woven together beautifully. It definitely deserves more than one read because you probably missed how some of the stories were connected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Children of Men&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Goodreads Summer Reading Challenge: It’s the End of the World&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In general, apocalyptic novels aren’t my favourite. So for this challenge I took the chance to read the book that inspired a movie I enjoyed of the same name. It turns out that the movie was quite different that the book (but that’s not really a surprise, is it?). Many of the elements from the book are in the movie, but with different characters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m glad I read a woman author for this challenge. It was fascinating perspective on an infertile human race. The parts that described dolls as desperate substitutes for real babies felt so creepy and heartbreaking. I wouldn’t read it again, but I might recommend it and maybe try to read more PD James?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Sleeper and the Spindle&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Goodreads Summer Reading Challenge: My, What Big Teeth You Have&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sleeping Beauty was never my favourite princess or story, so I was &lt;em&gt;so&lt;/em&gt; happy with this retelling. Neil Gaiman hasn’t disappointed me yet. Neither has Chris Riddell, the illustrator. This book is so short you should just go read it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cadillac Cathedral&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Goodreads Summer Reading Challenge: Into the Great Wide Open&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps this book wasn’t exactly set in the wilderness but there were rebellious acts in the relative wilderness of rural BC. It felt true to the Tom Petty song. I enjoyed this departure from a big city setting! Also it featured characters in retirement, and satisfyingly active ones. The perfect contrasting perspectiv eafter reading too much YA this week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book reminded how much I love friend visits on ordinary days when you or they are in the midst of chores. That’s when you know you’re good friends. Why wait for an “event” to hang out? So it pleased me to read the same sentiments in &lt;em&gt;Cadillac Cathedral&lt;/em&gt;. The other fun part for me were the mentions of Finnish culture and names which I was able to share with dear Finnish friend (and fellow bookworm). We’re already planning a &lt;em&gt;seisova pöytä&lt;/em&gt; (a kind of food spread/buffet).&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Reading Roundup 14]]></title><description><![CDATA[Fact: when you read six books in a week, there’s less time for writing about them. This week I’ll attempt to leave more time for writing…]]></description><link>https://voracious-bookworm.com/reading-roundup-14/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://voracious-bookworm.com/reading-roundup-14/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Fact: when you read six books in a week, there’s less time for writing about them. This week I’ll attempt to leave more time for writing!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Attachments&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Goodreads Summer Reading Challenge: Dear Pen Pal&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of my favourite books in elementary school was &lt;em&gt;Letters from Camp&lt;/em&gt; by Kate Klise, which was told through letters, notes, newspaper clippings, and other clippings. I was enchanted with the fact that you could tell an entire story with snippets of communication. So I was excited for this challenge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Attachments&lt;/em&gt; was told through a mix of emails (it’s a kind of letter right!?), and a limited third-person point-of-view. It was cute but I spent a bit of time cringing at the stereotypical IT guy depiction. This book did &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; age well with its mentions of Y2K. On the other hand it was fun to consider romance before the time of ubiquitous smartphones. Also it was Rainbow Rowell’s first book, I can forgive her. Otherwise I’d skip this book unless you feel nostalgic for 90s communication?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Crossover&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Goodreads Summer Reading Challenge: Sports-a-holic&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was not expecting a kids basketball book to be poetry-as-prose… so &lt;em&gt;The Crossover&lt;/em&gt; was a pleasant surprise! It reminded me of writing my own attempts at basketball-themed poetry in grade school. It’s a small book but manages to delve into fathers, sibling rivalry, and some young angst. All in free verse mind you. I’m filing this under favourite basketball stories!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Meanwhile&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Goodreads Summer Reading Challenge: Childhood Reboot&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Choose-your-own-adventure comic book! What more do I need to say? I read this book with bae and we both enjoyed it thoroughly. Give yourself a chunk of time to read it though, as the many storylines may frustrate you. Puzzle-lovers, put this on your TBR! (Yes, I know the challenge says &lt;em&gt;novel&lt;/em&gt; but trust me, this book requires more thinking than many novels.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grief is the Thing with Feathers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Goodreads Summer Reading Challenge: Father Knows Best&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This one brought on the feels. I purposely read about death (&lt;em&gt;From Here to Eternity&lt;/em&gt;) instead of grief for the Popsugar Reading Challenge and yet here I am, reviewing a book about grief. Like &lt;em&gt;The Crossover&lt;/em&gt;, this book used the lyrical quality of poetry-as-prose to tug on your heartstrings. I promise I didn’t pick two poetry-as-prose books this week on purpose!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn’t quite get the role of the crow in the book, probably because the main character is a Ted Hughes scholar and I have not read any Ted Hughes. (I did force myself through &lt;em&gt;Ariel&lt;/em&gt; by Sylvia Plath earlier this year.) I admire crows because they are wonderfully smart birds, but given the crow’s role in sadness in this book, I’m not tempted to read any Ted Hughes right now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, the contrast of the young boys’ grief compared to the father’s grief made the father’s grief that much stronger for me. And to think, I haven’t yet experienced this level of grief before. This will be on my list to read or suggest when that inevitable grief strikes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A note on the challenge category: Where are all the good dads in literature!?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rubyfruit Jungle&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Goodreads Summer Reading Challenge: Take Pride&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book made me think of &lt;em&gt;Peyton Place&lt;/em&gt;, which was banned in Canada at some point, because it was considered to be too scandalous. I can imagine Rubyfruit Jungle was considered scandalous at its publication due to its depiction of lesbian relationships. I’m sure the fact that title turned out to be the description of female gentalia made it even more offensive to some people, hehe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was my second read that centered around women loving women (the other being &lt;em&gt;Landing&lt;/em&gt; by Emma Donoghue, which I loved!), but it wasn’t only about that. I appreciated that Molly stayed true to herself throughout the book, whether it was about going to university or film school in New York. The sexism she experienced from getting into a predominantly (completely) men’s field reminded me of parts of tech industry I’m in today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before doing book challenges I used to want to pick books out “on my own”, like a hipster. Now I’m glad to have book challenges push me and give me an opportunity to read classics or seminal works like &lt;em&gt;Rubyfruit Jungle&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;99 Bottles of OOP&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Popsugar Reading Challenge: A book with song lyrics in the title&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I filled this challenge by accident, as this book was required reading for a workshop I got to do through work. It was so perfectly apt though, as the examples in the book centered around the lyrics of &lt;em&gt;99 Bottles&lt;/em&gt;. Turns out you can learn a lot of from one song :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Phew! That was an intense week of reading. And I passed 50 books read this year!&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Reading Roundup 13]]></title><description><![CDATA[Apparently travelling with friends means ice cream, kayaking, board games but no reading time. Whatever! I got quality over quantity this…]]></description><link>https://voracious-bookworm.com/reading-roundup-13/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://voracious-bookworm.com/reading-roundup-13/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 04 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Apparently travelling with friends means ice cream, kayaking, board games but no reading time. Whatever! I got quality over quantity this week 💖&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dianagabaldon.com/books/outlander-series/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Outlander&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Popsugar Reading Challenge: A book about time travel&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OMG. I &lt;em&gt;loved&lt;/em&gt; this book. It had a strong woman protagonist, sexy accents, sexy scenes, details galore, …
and more things that I can’t name because I’m so excited about the book!!!
I read this beautiful brick in two days! (I didn’t really know I was signing up for 600+ pages since I read the ebook version.)
It’s my first adult time-travelling book (I was going to say first overall, but then I remembered
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mollymoonsworld.com/the-books/molly-moon-books/&quot;&gt;Molly Moon&lt;/a&gt;) and I have to say I was skeptical that I would like it.
But ohhhh yes, I was proven wrong, very wrong. Reading until 4am to finish it wrong. Sometimes it’s unhealthy to be proven wrong. 😕&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s funny because while thinking about what I would write for this post, I realized how similiar it is to another one of my favourites: &lt;em&gt;Ransom My Heart&lt;/em&gt; by Meg Cabot.
I wonder how much of it was inspired by Outlander. Or maybe this is how most romances of this type are written.
Again, I thank my reading challenges for helping me try new reads!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, when I started raving about it to my fellow bookworms, they’d already read it (and the rest of the series!) and loved it. So you probably have as well.
But I don’t care that I’m late, I’m glad I discovered it!
And apparently the TV adaptation is great too (not that I’m going to watch it).
So if you haven’t already, go forth and experience it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://matthewquickwriter.com/novels/the-silver-linings-playbook/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Silver Linings Playbook&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Popsugar Reading Challenge: A book about mental health&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I’m extremely picky about which movies I watch, I often miss out on pop culture things. I can often fix that by reading the book
(which is usually the original anyway).
I did that with &lt;em&gt;Hidden Figures&lt;/em&gt; last year, and I’ll probably skip seeing &lt;em&gt;Crazy, Rich Asians&lt;/em&gt; since I already read and loved the book.
&lt;em&gt;The Silver Linings Playbook&lt;/em&gt; is the first book that’s made me want to see the movie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This novel is written from the first-person perspective of a person who has a mental illness.
I found this point-of-view to be refreshing, since you could see the struggle from the inside.
There were moments that made me laugh, but also many that broke my heart.
What I want to see is how they portrayed things from the outside in the movie (or did they?).
So while I do that, you can go and read that book :)&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Reading Roundup 12]]></title><description><![CDATA[I missed writing book reactions! Also I bumped into  Heather O’Neill  and I felt inspired to write more.
So here I am, back to writing about…]]></description><link>https://voracious-bookworm.com/reading-roundup-12/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://voracious-bookworm.com/reading-roundup-12/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 27 May 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I missed writing book reactions! Also I bumped into &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/lethal_heroine&quot;&gt;Heather O’Neill&lt;/a&gt; and I felt inspired to write more.
So here I am, back to writing about my week’s reads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://jessieannfoley.com/?page_id=47&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Carnival at Bray&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Popsugar Reading Challenge: A book set in the decade you were born&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was a fun read! It probably would have been one of my favourites if it had been released when I was in high school.
I’m a sucker for first love stories. Also I’ve been meaning to plan a trip to Ireland, and this book only fuels this wish even more.
The only question I’m left with now is how to pronounce Eoin. Oh Irish names &amp;#x3C;3&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Update: Apparently Eoin is like Owen 😍&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://heathbrothers.com/books/decisive/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Decisive: How to Make Better Choices in Life and Work&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Popsugar Reading Challenge: A book by two authors&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book was highly touted at work (and there were free copies to take), so I gave it a read.
There were plenty of actionable ideas in it, and quite applicable given that we all have thousands of decisions to make every day.
As someone who can get overwhelmed with the packed nature of non-fiction, I appreciated the chapter summaries.
Not the most enjoyable read of the week, but definitely useful and recommendable!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.simongarfield.com/pages/books/just_my_type.htm&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Just My Type: A Book About Fonts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Popsugar Reading Challenge: A microhistory&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I thought I was picky about fonts before… it’s much worse now. I loved this mish-mash of stories about type.
It put real humans behind the letters everyone sees! I was reminded of researching the mathematicians behind different formulas.
(Or maybe of a different microhistory I’ve read.) This book introduced me to the &lt;em&gt;world&lt;/em&gt; of type. It’s huge!
Thankfully we’re in the age of the Internet where I can simply search them online, not laboriously in doorstopper book.
I learned about the hate for Comic Sans and Arial, but also the love for Helvetica, and just how old some types are.
It even helped me choose the fonts for this new site (I ditched one because of its long commas).
So if you want to have a taste of the passion behind the shapes of letters, please read this book :)&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Hello World!]]></title><description><![CDATA[Exciting news!!! My book blog has a new home!
It even has a grown-up domain name (grown-up because I have to pay for it). Now that things…]]></description><link>https://voracious-bookworm.com/hello-world/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://voracious-bookworm.com/hello-world/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 24 May 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Exciting news!!! My book blog has a new home!
It even has a grown-up domain name (grown-up because I have to pay for it).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that things are setup, I’m looking forward to writing more.
Even more so that it’ll be in my favourite (arguably archaic) text-editor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, here’s a cat I met today! 🏀&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a
    class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-link&quot;
    href=&quot;/static/cat-020e4aa7314b54c1132ff1bcab5833ca-11eb7.jpg&quot;
    style=&quot;display: block&quot;
    target=&quot;_blank&quot;
    rel=&quot;noopener&quot;
  &gt;
  
  &lt;span
    class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-wrapper&quot;
    style=&quot;position: relative; display: block; ; max-width: 590px; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&quot;
  &gt;
    &lt;span
      class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-background-image&quot;
      style=&quot;padding-bottom: 100%; position: relative; bottom: 0; left: 0; background-image: url(&apos;data:image/jpeg;base64,/9j/2wBDABALDA4MChAODQ4SERATGCgaGBYWGDEjJR0oOjM9PDkzODdASFxOQERXRTc4UG1RV19iZ2hnPk1xeXBkeFxlZ2P/2wBDARESEhgVGC8aGi9jQjhCY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2P/wgARCAAUABQDASIAAhEBAxEB/8QAGAABAQEBAQAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAUDAgT/xAAWAQEBAQAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAABAAL/2gAMAwEAAhADEAAAAaU7uK597BVvA0Zgf//EABsQAAICAwEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAECAAMEEBEU/9oACAEBAAEFAjyW5KpPYZbWzl0ItOOdOO6//8QAFxEBAAMAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAEQIf/aAAgBAwEBPwFiK//EABgRAAIDAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAARARAh/9oACAECAQE/AWjSa//EABwQAAICAgMAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAABEBEhMgIiUf/aAAgBAQAGPwLBXHszVGGyqNlCfkf/xAAdEAACAgMAAwAAAAAAAAAAAAABEQAhEDFBUZHR/9oACAEBAAE/IVfUK1dboTy+8x1WTT2YZGhJnGXAwLsqx//aAAwDAQACAAMAAAAQX/8AvP/EABkRAQACAwAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAEAEBEhMf/aAAgBAwEBPxAB3MR1X//EABkRAAIDAQAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAABEBEhMf/aAAgBAgEBPxBtgs8R/8QAHRABAAIBBQEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAQARITFBUXGBYf/aAAgBAQABPxCw5YMuyVVFqKe271AzBfkqD2RdQJ5FnABxbBppGVEzHjaBjfRESf/Z&apos;); background-size: cover; display: block;&quot;
    &gt;
      &lt;img
        class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-image&quot;
        style=&quot;width: 100%; height: 100%; margin: 0; vertical-align: middle; position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; box-shadow: inset 0px 0px 0px 400px white;&quot;
        alt=&quot;Cat&quot;
        title=&quot;&quot;
        src=&quot;/static/cat-020e4aa7314b54c1132ff1bcab5833ca-f8fb9.jpg&quot;
        srcset=&quot;/static/cat-020e4aa7314b54c1132ff1bcab5833ca-e8976.jpg 148w,
/static/cat-020e4aa7314b54c1132ff1bcab5833ca-63df2.jpg 295w,
/static/cat-020e4aa7314b54c1132ff1bcab5833ca-f8fb9.jpg 590w,
/static/cat-020e4aa7314b54c1132ff1bcab5833ca-85e3d.jpg 885w,
/static/cat-020e4aa7314b54c1132ff1bcab5833ca-d1924.jpg 1180w,
/static/cat-020e4aa7314b54c1132ff1bcab5833ca-9452e.jpg 1770w,
/static/cat-020e4aa7314b54c1132ff1bcab5833ca-11eb7.jpg 3036w&quot;
        sizes=&quot;(max-width: 590px) 100vw, 590px&quot;
      /&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
  
  &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Reading Roundup 11]]></title><description><![CDATA[I’m done the 2018 Read Harder Challenge! It took me 71 days, so a book almost every three days.
That means I finished two months earlier…]]></description><link>https://voracious-bookworm.com/reading-roundup-11/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://voracious-bookworm.com/reading-roundup-11/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I’m done the 2018 Read Harder Challenge! It took me 71 days, so a book almost every three days.
That means I finished two months earlier than last year, and I am free to go on to the next challenge!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Lover&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Read Harder Challenge: A book of genre fiction in translation (romance)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book reminded me of &lt;em&gt;That Summer in Provincetown&lt;/em&gt;
(which is fitting, because that was the first read of the Read Harder Challenge, and this is my last read of it!!!)
in the vignette-style, the re-telling of the same events in different ways, and the setting in Southeast Asia.
I thought this one was less successful though. Perhaps because this one is fancier (it won the &lt;em&gt;Prix Goncourt&lt;/em&gt;).
Or maybe because it went over my head? It could just be literature that I am unequipped to examine. The story is sad but not surprising.
I completely understand why the content was controversial. Maybe that’s why people read it. Y’all can find out for yourselves. :)&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Reading Roundup 10]]></title><description><![CDATA[This week’s verdict: travel is excellent for my reading progress! It was fun to be in a cold country, yet reading about sweating in the hot…]]></description><link>https://voracious-bookworm.com/reading-roundup-10/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://voracious-bookworm.com/reading-roundup-10/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;This week’s verdict: travel is excellent for my reading progress! It was fun to be in a cold country, yet reading about sweating in the hot, Sicilian sun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Open House&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Read Harder Challenge: An Oprah Book Club selection&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of the Oprah Book Club selections looked like intensely emotional reads, and this one wasn’t an exception. I think I was able to stomach it because I’ve never gone through a divorce, but oh, how I felt the hurt in this one! But also the growth! The heart-wrenching, cringey beginning made the character development way more satisfying. It was definitely an inner conflict kind of book, the grown-up version to my favourite kinds of books as a teenager. This is the best part about reading - the lives you get to live without really living them (or maybe the worst part!?).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Auntie Poldi and the Sicilian Lions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Read Harder Challenge: A book with a female protagonist over the age of 60&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went on a Miss Marple-esque (older women detectives) streak! I read a Miss Marple short, then the first Aunty Lee, and then this lovely tale. It’s funny that I ended up reading this story right after Aunty Lee’s Delights because there are many similarities - the age of the investigators, the digressions on food, and the hot, humid settings (Singapore and Sicily - another similarity!). While I enjoyed both books, this one satisfied my mystery critic much better. It all came full circle! :D&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book makes me want to visit Sicily, go mushroom-picking, listen to elders argue about food, sit on the beach, drink great wine, and be passionate in general. That’s what it inspired in me, which is funny, because usually mysteries are all about the characters. And yes, the characters in the book are great! That’s why I mentioned listening to arguments and being passionate. But the descriptions of Italy were mouth-watering. Lit, as the cool people would say? So go read this book unless you want to avoid wanting to go to Italy. :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(P.S. This one was originally my choice for “A book of genre fiction in translation”, but it was much easier to find more genre fiction in translation than books with female protagonists over the age of 60 :()&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aunty Lee’s Delights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Read Harder Challenge: A mystery by a person of color or LGBTQ+ author&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I’m to be honest here, I might have chosen this novel because I had such a fun time reading a Singaporean series (&lt;em&gt;Crazy, Rich Asians&lt;/em&gt;) last year. What convinced me even more was that it was endorsed by Louise Penny, the popular Canadian mystery author (who I have yet to read, please forgive me). I found out in the notes at the end of the book that Ovidia Yu actually was inspired to write the novel because of Louise Penny! Ahh, the connections!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book was an enjoyable read. I loved the array of characters: unlikely investigator and chef Aunty Lee, her ever-helpful, Watson-like Filipina maid, the social-climbing daughter-in-law that reminded me of &lt;em&gt;Crazy, Rich Asians&lt;/em&gt; series, and so many more. I loved that Aunty Lee’s superpower is her cooking, and that food elements are weaved throughout the whole book. It’s even mentioned that her notes are reminiscent of a recipe :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a treat to read a mystery featuring people of colour. I guess I’ve been reading a lot of old-school mysteries set in Britain or Europe. Thank you Read Harder Challenge for making me discover other delights!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wasn’t a huge fan of how the investigation finished. It felt like many of the details came out at the end, and I find that the most satisfying mysteries are those that tie up clues from the beginning. Or maybe my expectations are at peak Agatha Christie level ;) Even so, I had fun reading this story, and I look forward to reading the rest of the series!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(P.S. I originally set out to read &lt;em&gt;The Summer We Got Free&lt;/em&gt; by Mia McKenzie since it’s written by a badass PoC and LGBTQ+ but it was unavailable at the three library systems I have access to!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;True Grit&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Read Harder Challenge: A western&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had to choose this book when I realized that main character is a young woman seeking to avenge her father. How many westerns feature that!? I wouldn’t actually know because I don’t read or watch a lot of westerns. I do know that revenge, outlaws, gold, and horses are common threads though, and this book has ‘em all!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While it was fun to have a woman lead, I did enjoy &lt;em&gt;The Sisters Brothers&lt;/em&gt; more than this book. I remember laughing more. And I hated the description of the amputation… Maybe I shouldn’t watch the movie then. A version of &lt;em&gt;The Sisters Brothers&lt;/em&gt; is due to come out this year though! So I’d say if you wanna dip your toes into a western, this ain’t bad but I liked &lt;em&gt;The Sisters Brothers&lt;/em&gt; better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;July’s People&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Read Harder Challenge: A book set in or about one of the five BRICS countries (Brazil, Russia, India, China, or South Africa)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I chose this book because it’s by Nadine Gordimer, a South African winner of the Nobel Prize in Literature. I love crossing off two challenge requirements with one book! It also makes choosing books easier &amp;#x3C;3 I actually chose &lt;em&gt;No Time Like the Present&lt;/em&gt; first, which is also by Gordimer, but I found it the writing style hard to follow. Maybe if I’d read it during my travels I might have tried harder to get through it ;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This novel was one vision Gordimer had of the end of apartheid in South Africa, about a decade before it happened, where a civil war caused a white family to flee into hiding in their black employee’s village. I’m not familiar with a lot of this part of history, so I ended up reading more on South Africa to give myself more context for the read. Yay for books that expand our horizons!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book only told the the story of one family, but this was so powerful, because you can feel the growing helplessness of the parents. I found it quite accurate that the kids in the family easily adjusted, picking up the customs, the language, and of course, playmates. While I can’t say that I enjoyed reading this book since the topics were quite heavy, but I’m glad I did because it allowed me to learn more about another corner of our planet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Old Chief Mshlanga&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Read Harder Challenge: A book of colonial or postcolonial literature&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I chose this little story to introduce myself to Doris Lessing, another Nobel Prize-winning woman, and I wasn’t disappointed. In a small amount of text she was able to dive into colonial tensions without naming specific places. I also got another coming-of-age story, which I loved in this case, because the girl’s realization of injustice feels more emotional. I think I’ll have to pick up more Doris Lessing!&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Reading Roundup 9]]></title><description><![CDATA[Week 9 features only one book, a much denser non-fiction story. It often takes me longer to read non-fiction, and this one was no exception…]]></description><link>https://voracious-bookworm.com/reading-roundup-9/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://voracious-bookworm.com/reading-roundup-9/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Week 9 features only one book, a much denser non-fiction story. It often takes me longer to read non-fiction, and this one was no exception.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Soul of a New Machine&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Read Harder Challenge: An assigned book you never finished&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book was assigned for a bonus mark on the final exam in my computer systems class. I’d say that the five core courses I was taking that semester (my first in Computer Science) got in the way of reading it. I don’t think I would have appreciated it as much back then! My mom would say it’s because I’ve gotten nerdier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book was an adventure into the development of a new computer. It made me appreciate how far we’ve come in technology, and glad that working in computers doesn’t require the crazy dedication described in the book (though there are definitely people in tech who still work that much!). I loved finding out about Betty Shanahan, the one woman on the team, the references to Adventure, an early text adventure game (if you’ve never tried one, please do!!!), and clever analogies by Terry Pratchett. Basically, it pleased the nerd in me (the computer one, not the bio one).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re worried that it’s too nerdy for you though, remember that it won a Pulitzer Prize, and that’s for a good reason: you’re kept on the edge of your seat, and the technical details are explained in an approachable way. It got me inspired for my own teaching - earlier this year, I had to explain some of the concepts mentioned in the book to my students. I guess now I know why it was assigned ;)&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>