<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Voracious Bookworm]]></title><description><![CDATA[writings about devoured books]]></description><link>https://voracious-bookworm.com</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Oct 2018 14:04:00 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[Reading Roundup 33]]></title><description><![CDATA[I read ZERO books last week. That’s a first for this half of the year! The wave of busyness crashed over me and the books were let go. Good…]]></description><link>https://voracious-bookworm.com/reading-roundup-33/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://voracious-bookworm.com/reading-roundup-33/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 28 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I read ZERO books last week. That’s a first for this half of the year! The wave of busyness crashed over me and the books were let go. Good thing I’m ahead of schedule for my challenge!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Haroun and the Sea of Stories&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Popsugar Reading Challenge: A book mentioned in another book&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This challenge again! I should be keeping a running list of them because it’s &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; the easiest to source, and I like to pick from books that I’ve read.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I pulled this story from &lt;em&gt;The Borrowers&lt;/em&gt;, which is about a librarian, so it had many mentions. I’d already read many of them, but this book was perfect because I haven’t read any Salman Rushie yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Haroun&lt;/em&gt; is one of those books that’s written for kids but still fun as an adult. I was most reminded of &lt;em&gt;The Phantom Tollbooth&lt;/em&gt; because of its personification of books and other storytelling devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m also reminded of &lt;em&gt;The Palace of Illusions&lt;/em&gt; by Chitra Banerjee Divakaruni for the elements of Indian culture. My next choice of mythologies will have to be from farther east.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Art of Learning: An Inner Journey to Optimal Performance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Popsugar Reading Challenge: A book with an ugly cover&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another challenge that makes me judge books by their covers :( I chose this cover because the are two pictures on it, one of them has text you’re supposed to read all over it, I don’t understand why there’s gradient, and the quote at the top is distracting. Enough reasons?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book was another one suggested by execs at work. To be honest, I think I find more inspiration in everyday people around me than in child prodigies or world champions. People overcome adversity in so many ways and I’m more interested in the everyday experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not everyone is single-mindedly aiming for world championships, but this was a jaunt into the mind of someone who did.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Reading Roundup 32]]></title><description><![CDATA[I’m in that “last stretch of a book challenge” frenzy (imagine the FINISH HIM! cry in Mortal Kombat ;) ). It’s to the point where I have the…]]></description><link>https://voracious-bookworm.com/reading-roundup-32/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://voracious-bookworm.com/reading-roundup-32/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I’m in that “last stretch of a book challenge” frenzy (imagine the FINISH HIM! cry in Mortal Kombat ;) ). It’s to the point where I have the same book on hold at two libraries 🙊 And anxiously creeping on what people are reading on the subway (it’s for a reading challenge, okay?). I’m almost there though!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;James and the Giant Peach&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Popsugar Reading Challenge: A book that is also a stage play or musical&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I struggled with this challenge because it was mostly classic novels on the lists I found. Not super appealing to me, so I chose the throw it back to a play I remember being in as a kid! I don’t remember which character I was though 🤔&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s funny how many details I’d forgotten about the book - James’ aunts, the seagulls, and the Gloworm. Definitely worth the re-read of one of my fave children’s book authors. Maybe next up is Matilda!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chocolat&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Popsugar Reading Challenge: A book made into a movie that you’ve already seen&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another tougher challenge for me, since I don’t watch a lot of movies. I had to read a bunch of lists to find one that I felt like experiencing the story again (albeit in a different way).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Watching the movie first ruined this book for me. I kept looking for details from the movie! It mostly made me want to watch the movie again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book did have mouthwatering descriptions of food and desserts though. I also enjoyed the extra details on Armande the grandmother. Overall a fun read - but probably better if you read it first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Bat&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Popsugar Reading Challenge: Nordic noir&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hated the callous treatment of the love interest in this story. It just wasn’t believable to me that someone would agree to be serial killer bait. He might as well have &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Women_in_Refrigerators&quot;&gt;put her in a refrigerator&lt;/a&gt; 🙄 Ugh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Otherwise, if you’re expecting a story set in Norway, this is not the one. There are a lot of twists and turns but it’s all set in Australia. Similar to Louise Penny’s debut &lt;em&gt;Still Life&lt;/em&gt;, I can tell that this is Nesbo’s best work but it’s fun to see the beginning!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Modern Romance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Popsugar Reading Challenge: A past Goodreads Choice Awards winner&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meh. If you’ve already read Helen Fisher, Esther Perel, and Sheena Iyengar, this book isn’t much of a revelation. The best parts were the anecdotes from the focus groups (that were part of the research of this book) and the insights into the culture of romance in Japan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It &lt;em&gt;was&lt;/em&gt; interesting to read from a man’s perspective, especially given that Ansari is wont to give examples from his own life. I’ve mostly read and listened to women on the subject, so this was new for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think I’ll go back to listening to mythologies though - it’s more apt for storytelling out loud, and I’m not missing any graphs.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Reading Roundup 31]]></title><description><![CDATA[Happy Thanksgiving! 🍁 Hope my fellow Canadians got some reading in during the long weekend 📖 My reading choices this week were focused on…]]></description><link>https://voracious-bookworm.com/reading-roundup-31/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://voracious-bookworm.com/reading-roundup-31/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 07 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Happy Thanksgiving! 🍁 Hope my fellow Canadians got some reading in during the long weekend 📖 My reading choices this week were focused on ease and enjoyment. There are so many heartbreaking books out there, but I can always take a break from them with lighter books.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Still Life&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Popsugar Reading Challenge: Your favourite prompt from the 2015, 2016, or 2017 Popsugar Reading Challenges&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;2017: The first book in a series you haven’t read before&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I finally read a Louise Penny book! It was recommended by my mom and honestly, I should have read it earlier since it’s (almost) a local read. On the other hand, the timing was perfect since the story is starts on Thanksgiving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Local reads are fun because you recognize all the little details. In this case, it was the sprinkling of French, the Quebecker swears, and the places in Montréal. It made me want to go drive through the Eastern Townships - especially in the current foliage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel like this isn’t the best Penny book yet, but I’m glad I started at the beginning so I can experience the improvement. A very soft way to say that there were some things in the plot that didn’t feel so smooth, but I still want to read more!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is why I picked this challenge as my fave one - if you pick a good book, it’s a gift that comes with more books.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Akata Witch&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Popsugar Reading Challenge: A book recommended by someone else taking the Popsugar Reading Challenge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you to my fellow voracious reader Chloe for this excellent suggestion! I was probably going to get to this eventually because I love Nnedi Okorafor but it got fast-tracked by recommendation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just like the Binti series, there’s so much to &lt;em&gt;Akata Witch&lt;/em&gt; that feels so original. There’s the girl witch thing, then you add her badass soccer skills, the focus on learning and teamwork and then I’m done a book in one sitting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good thing there’s more! I have to pace myself on Okorafor books or I’ll be sad that there aren’t more out right now - just like I’ve been doing with Heather O’Neill books. &amp;#x3C;3&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Something in Between&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Popsugar Reading Challenge: A book tied to your ancestry&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I definitely have to be in a specific mood to read YA these days (otherwise I’ll roll my eyes out of their sockets), but this one caught me at the right time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To my bae, this story was a squealer (one that made me squeeeee in delight). It may have been cheesy and predictable but I adore immigrant stories and this one featured a Filipina!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s nothing like seeing your culture represented in writing (when it normally isn’t). I loved seeing the words lumpia, Ilocano, and anak. Can I have more please?&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Reading Roundup 30]]></title><description><![CDATA[I was feeling bad that I only read one book this week but it turns out that I read eight books in September so I can’t really be…]]></description><link>https://voracious-bookworm.com/reading-roundup-30/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://voracious-bookworm.com/reading-roundup-30/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 30 Sep 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I was feeling bad that I only read one book this week but it turns out that I read eight books in September so I can’t really be disappointed! Busyness comes in waves (&lt;em&gt;she says as the force of October is hurtling towards her&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Together Tea&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Popsugar Reading Challenge: A book with alliteration in the title&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book was perfect to fulfill the alliteration category since one of the side characters spoke with an excess of alliteration - I got more than I signed up for! (Kinda like-but not as intense as-the first speech from V in &lt;em&gt;V for Vendetta&lt;/em&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was &lt;em&gt;a lot&lt;/em&gt; jam-packed into this book. It reminded me of &lt;em&gt;Persepolis&lt;/em&gt; (for the parts about the Iranian Revolution), &lt;em&gt;Daring to Drive&lt;/em&gt; (for the impact on women in rising Islamic conservatism), &lt;em&gt;Travelling with Pomegranates&lt;/em&gt; (for the alternating mother/daughter perspectives), and &lt;em&gt;A Bollywood Affair&lt;/em&gt; (for the cross-oceanic love story). Phew!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m glad there are stories to read about immigration and feeling between cultures, so this is a good one for you if you like that.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Reading Roundup 29]]></title><description><![CDATA[Fall is here! Which I wish it meant cozying up to books and hot tea, but really means that teaching duties are picking up, volunteer…]]></description><link>https://voracious-bookworm.com/reading-roundup-29/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://voracious-bookworm.com/reading-roundup-29/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 23 Sep 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Fall is here! Which I wish it meant cozying up to books and hot tea, but really means that teaching duties are picking up, volunteer meetings have been organized, and there are so many shows to go to. I don’t really live in an introverted city, hehe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vagina Monologues&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Popsugar Reading Challenge: A book from a celebrity book club&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It took me a few chapters in this book to make me remember that I’d already read it before, oops! I must have read it too fast last time. I’m glad I have Goodreads to help me keep track now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book made me want to go see a Vagina Monologues show. I’m sure there would be many kindred spirits :) It’s just not the same to imagine the performance from written words.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m glad to live where I do, where in lieu of the usual penis graffiti on political posters, it’s been vaginas. It’s refreshing. ({*})&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Void Moon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Popsugar Reading Challenge: A book about a heist&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wow! This book made me miss my metro stop twice in one morning. Soooooo engrossing, like a heist book should be, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After seeing Ocean’s 8 in theatres this summer, (which is a big deal for me, I almost never go!) I had to pick a heist book that featured a woman and &lt;em&gt;Void Moon&lt;/em&gt; did not disappoint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite including descriptions of tech and being almost 20 years old, the book aged well. Believable enough for me, though maybe that says more about what I know of thieving technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m sad there are no more books featuring Cassie Black, but maybe I’ll have to try another one of Connelly’s books.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Reading Roundup 28]]></title><description><![CDATA[The other day I saw a canvas bag with the slogan: READ MORE WOMEN. I want it because I’ve done so this year and discovered so much. I want…]]></description><link>https://voracious-bookworm.com/reading-roundup-28/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://voracious-bookworm.com/reading-roundup-28/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;The other day I saw a canvas bag with the slogan: READ MORE WOMEN. I want it because I’ve done so this year and discovered so much. I want others to do the same!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Circe&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Popsugar Reading Challenge: A book published in 2018&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A banquet of Greek mythology woven around the goddess Circe, this book tackles some of the toughest struggles of being a woman and human, from motherhood to rape to mortality. I think this starts a personal trend of &lt;em&gt;listening&lt;/em&gt; to mythology books.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I enjoyed this book, though it was a little too long for me. It was fun to see gods from a different, less fun-loving perspective. I learned of a few other myths I’d never heard of before, despite a period of voraciously reading Greek myths in Grade 6. [SPOILER: Did anyone else get the &lt;em&gt;Tuck Everlasting&lt;/em&gt; feels at the end?]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I felt a dark vibe from this story similar to &lt;em&gt;Norse Mythology&lt;/em&gt;, but I wasn’t expecting it from Greek mythology! Perhaps I would have enjoyed it more had I not been reading the even heavier &lt;em&gt;Bad Feminist&lt;/em&gt; concurrently. One can only absorb so much weight at a time &amp;#x3C;/3&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So now I’m off to go read something funny!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Lover’s Dictionary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Popsugar Reading Challenge: A book you borrowed or was given to you as a gift&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found my lighter read in this precious book &amp;#x3C;3 It features a word per page with a description that captures a slice of love - happy or otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The descriptions range from one sentence to a full paragraph - a testament to how much one word can inspire. I enjoyed this so much because of its parallels to improv. Often it’s just one word that sparks a &lt;em&gt;whole&lt;/em&gt; scene!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m glad I picked this up on a whim - I’ve been sticking religiously to books that fit my reading challenges (though this one fit a challenge anyway).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Daring to Drive&lt;/strong&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the third piece of literature/art I’ve experienced from Saudi Arabia. The first was the movie &lt;em&gt;Wadjda&lt;/em&gt;, the first movie filmed entirely in Saudi (and directed by a woman!) which I recommend wholeheartedly. The other was &lt;em&gt;Girls of Riyadh&lt;/em&gt;, by Rajaa al-Sanea, which gave another insider peek into Saudi culture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found all of these pieces difficult to read/watch (but also fascinating) because of all the obstacles Saudi women face in their day-to-day lives, and the extreme inequality between genders. This was especially true for &lt;em&gt;Daring to Drive&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Women driving is no big deal right? That’s until you understand the context, which is what most of this book was. It was a dive into the culture that forbids women in so many ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the hardest chapters for me was the one on female circumcision (or more accurately, genital mutilation). It comes early in the book, and it surprised me because I still thought this book was about driving. No details are spared.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I loved that al-Sharif studied Computer Science like me! It was fun to read the details she shared about her work. She’s a CS role model I’d love to share to all my fellow women in tech. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All-in-all reading this book made me feel immensely grateful for where I was born and now live. &amp;#x3C;3&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Reading Roundup 27]]></title><description><![CDATA[I’m slowly making my through the  Circe  audiobook, so I had to pair it with some non-fiction (or poetry - but poetry collections are also…]]></description><link>https://voracious-bookworm.com/reading-roundup-27/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://voracious-bookworm.com/reading-roundup-27/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I’m slowly making my through the &lt;em&gt;Circe&lt;/em&gt; audiobook, so I had to pair it with some non-fiction (or poetry - but poetry collections are also slow-going).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bad Feminist&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Popsugar Reading Challenge: A book about feminism&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have so many FEELS about this book. The best part of it for me was the fresh perspective. Roxane Gay is an unapologetic voice for so many unrepresented people. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The collection is personal and unabashed. It made me feel the humanities gap in my STEM education, in my writing and analysis. Good thing learning doesn’t stop in school ;)&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Reading Roundup 26]]></title><description><![CDATA[I completed the Goodreads Ultimate Summer Reading Challenge! It took a lot of planning and research and a few trips to the library, but I…]]></description><link>https://voracious-bookworm.com/reading-roundup-26/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://voracious-bookworm.com/reading-roundup-26/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 02 Sep 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I completed the Goodreads Ultimate Summer Reading Challenge! It took a lot of planning and research and a few trips to the library, but I did it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A Good Indian Wife&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Goodreads Summer Reading Challenge: Let’s Get It On&lt;/em&gt;
I really disliked the main guy in this book, the fancy doctor with his fancy red Porsche. It took him the whole book to change, and by the end I wasn’t convinced. Not your typical romance for sure!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, it was fun to read about another culture, especially centered around culture clash and immigration. It reminded me of Bend It Like Beckham, one of my favourite movies about being caught between two cultures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which reminds me now that I have yet to see Crazy Rich Asians!!! I’ve heard such good things about it. Particularly about Awkwafina, who I’ve loved for years &amp;#x3C;3 I’m thankful for more Asian representation in the media :D&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;lobster is the best medicine&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Popsugar Reading Challenge: A book with an animal in the title&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been a fan of Liz Climo for a while! It was fun to read a whole collection of her comics. Plus there’s just something extra nice about reading comics in print.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Her use of animals makes the old biology student in me happy :D (Low-key reminds me of Telus commercials too hehe). It’s been a while since I read a bio book, maybe I should find another to read…&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Reading Roundup 25]]></title><description><![CDATA[This week I’m grateful for my reading habit. Despite being extra busy this week, I managed to finish a few books! The trick is to  always…]]></description><link>https://voracious-bookworm.com/reading-roundup-25/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://voracious-bookworm.com/reading-roundup-25/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 26 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;This week I’m grateful for my reading habit. Despite being extra busy this week, I managed to finish a few books! The trick is to &lt;em&gt;always have a book&lt;/em&gt; (and have a bae that joins you in reading books before bed &amp;#x3C;3).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Captain Pantoja and the Special Service&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Goodreads Summer Reading Challenge: Read the World&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think I really like epistolary novels! This one snuck (sneaked?) into my reading list without me choosing it for its letters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best parts of this book were the letters of the title character to his military superiors detailing the needs of his &lt;em&gt;special&lt;/em&gt; service in the most clinical manner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were some sections that were so hard to read because they switched contexts (characters and location) by the paragraph. The only indications were the names of the characters. I think a little bit of formatting could have helped readability without losing the desired weaving of scenes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite this, I laughed (out loud) so much reading this book (and my bae can attest to this). It may not have been the top Mario Vargas Llosa book, but I enjoyed it immensely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In Praise of the Stepmother&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Goodreads Summer Reading Challenge: Memories&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn’t buy any books on my vacations this year so I decided to do a re-read for this challenge. &lt;em&gt;In Praise of the Stepmother&lt;/em&gt; was one of the books I bought on the eve of my backpacking trip to Peru.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the book that introduced me to Mario Vargas Llosa and erotic &lt;em&gt;literature&lt;/em&gt;. It’s the one I finished on the plane there! And now Vargas Llosa is one of my faves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a re-read I found myself appreciating the writing more and wondering how it is to read it in Spanish. I rediscovered the word &lt;em&gt;scabrous&lt;/em&gt;. What a salacious, scabrous story. :p&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Obstacle Is The Way&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Goodreads Summer Reading Challenge: Lucky to Have You&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is one of the books I have access to through the collection of books recommended by execs at my job. I’m lucky to have a culture of reading at work, and free books!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, &lt;em&gt;The Obstacle Is The Way&lt;/em&gt; was not the most impactful read for me. I think it’s meant to be an intro or a modern take on Stoicism but even the author says it’s best to read the original texts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I could see this book inspiring some people but to be honest, I’m tired of reading about (white) men’s success stories. It dominates our culture and you’ll hear about them anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I felt a lot more motivated by the stories of the women I read in &lt;em&gt;Rad Women Worldwide&lt;/em&gt;. They &lt;em&gt;definitely&lt;/em&gt; faced obstacles that helped them succeed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Flaming Iguanas&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Goodreads Summer Reading Challenge: Time of Our Lives&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It takes me so long to read my own books. I said that I’d started this one on June 3rd but really, I only got into it August 23rd. There’s no deadline so there’s no sense of urgency!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I’m glad to have bought and read this book. It reads like a stream of consciousness story while following Tomato (the main character) through America.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I loved how unapologetic it was, in its feminism, sexuality, and unstructured form. The drawings and art were a treat. Now I want to go on my own road trip adventure!&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Reading Roundup 24]]></title><description><![CDATA[It feels like September bustle has hit me early this year! Course prep, website updates, signing up to the next session of improv classes…]]></description><link>https://voracious-bookworm.com/reading-roundup-24/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://voracious-bookworm.com/reading-roundup-24/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;It feels like September bustle has hit me early this year! Course prep, website updates, signing up to the next session of improv classes… There’s a lot to do and I’m excited to settle into a less harried routine and be able to read in peace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Beauty Queens&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Goodreads Summer Reading Challenge: Stranded&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was so skeptical of this book by its cover, and my association of Libba Bray with period fiction. I’m so glad I stuck with it because it was a riot to read! I laughed and giggled and &lt;em&gt;had&lt;/em&gt; to share parts with fellow readers throughout the book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was glad that it followed a diversity of girls and tackled issues like race and beauty culture and sexuality. The first half read a lot easier than the end (there were a lot of loose ends to tie up), but I was so invested in the characters, I wanted to know what happened in the end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The “commercial breaks” as parodies of beauty ads were the best! So hilarious! I would watch subscribe to a YouTube channel of those :D&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Reading Roundup 23]]></title><description><![CDATA[Only six books left in my Goodreads Summer Reading Challenge! When I started the summer I wasn’t sure if I could (or even should) do it but…]]></description><link>https://voracious-bookworm.com/reading-roundup-23/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://voracious-bookworm.com/reading-roundup-23/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Only six books left in my Goodreads Summer Reading Challenge! When I started the summer I wasn’t sure if I could (or even should) do it but now I’m so glad I did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Wangs vs. the World&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Goodreads Summer Reading Challenge: Life is a Highway&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I forgot to write a review of this last week! Perhaps I’m reading too fast (but thank goodness for Goodreads to help me track things).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was a fun romp around the US with an Asian-American family. It dealt with the 2008 financial crisis in a way that reminded me of the movie &lt;em&gt;The Big Short&lt;/em&gt; but had echoes of the privileges I read about in &lt;em&gt;Seating Arrangements&lt;/em&gt;, which I read earlier this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I enjoyed the different perspectives of the family, and loved the portrayal of Asians as capable artists, which is a narrative that feels missing from the mainstream of our culture (and that makes me glad for K-pop).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So much love to all the Asian-heritage authors I’ve been reading lately, please keep telling stories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Boy Erased&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Goodreads Summer Reading Challenge: The Book Is Always Better&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In general, if you ask if I’ve seen a movie, I probably haven’t (ignore the previous review). I might have read the book though. This challenge called for a book turning into a movie this year. From &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bookbub.com/blog/2017/12/26/book-adaptations-2018-movies&quot;&gt;this list&lt;/a&gt;, I chose &lt;em&gt;Boy Erased&lt;/em&gt; (because I’ve already read &lt;em&gt;A Wrinkle in Time&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Crazy Rich Asians&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Monster&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book felt way too long for an experience that lasted little over a week. It started out interesting but there were so many flashbacks that it lost steam for me. I appreciated the raw feelings and honesty, but honestly, it felt like it would have been better at half the length.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I won’t be watching the movie (though I normally wouldn’t anyway).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rad Women Worldwide&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Goodreads Summer Reading Challenge: Girl Power&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I picked this book on a whim from the suggestions in Libby (the e-library app), and it was totally worth it! It’s a shallow, accessible dive into the lives of badass women from around the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a great mix of adventurers, artists, scientists, and much more. Definitely recommend to all the girls as a starting point to learning more about great and diverse women in history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best part for me was learning about Fe Del Mundo, the first woman to attend Harvard Medical because they mistook her name to be a man’s name. Hah! They kept her because she was so smart, but it still took 10 years for women to regularly be accepted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;later, at the bar&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Goodreads Summer Reading Challenge: It’s 12 O’clock Somewhere&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For some reason, I wasn’t expecting a book set in a bar to feature so much drinking, but &lt;em&gt;later, at the bar&lt;/em&gt; surprised me. In a good way!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book features humans who happen to drink a lot and are unapologetic about it. It’s a series of stories that peek into their lives, their heartbreaks, flaws, and relationships.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first I was put off by the alcoholism, but then I appreciated the honesty and lack of judgment in the writing. &lt;em&gt;Rebecca Barry&lt;/em&gt; just tells their stories. A quick read that’s worth it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Norse Mythology&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Goodreads Summer Reading Challenge: Listen To Me&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I haven’t really gotten into audiobooks because I like seeing words and get distracted when I’m just listening to something. Good thing there are challenges to push me into trying them again right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the reasons I chose &lt;em&gt;Norse Mythology&lt;/em&gt; for this challenge is because Neil Gaiman reads it himself. The other reason is that I love Neil Gaiman. (Also PSA: I did not listen to this on Audible, my library has audiobooks to borrow &lt;em&gt;for free&lt;/em&gt;!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Norse Mythology&lt;/em&gt; is relatively dark compared to my experiences with Greek/Roman mythology. I suspect it’s due to the harsher climate of the Nordic countries. While I didn’t love the dark stories, I thoroughly enjoyed Gaiman’s reading of it. I was engaged and I’m glad to know the stories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After this, I’m totally down to listen to another audiobook. It’s much easier to consume in the subway.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Reading Roundup 22]]></title><description><![CDATA[This month I had most of my reads lined up for me, and it’s been really nice to finish a book and have a few choices ready (but not  too…]]></description><link>https://voracious-bookworm.com/reading-roundup-22/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://voracious-bookworm.com/reading-roundup-22/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;This month I had most of my reads lined up for me, and it’s been really nice to finish a book and have a few choices ready (but not &lt;em&gt;too&lt;/em&gt; many, that might cause some paralysis of choice ;) ) Again, yay for challenges that help me decide what to read!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enchanted, Inc.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Goodreads Summer Reading Challenge: Unshelve It&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The explanation for this challenge is to “Read a book that’s been sitting on your Goodreads shelf for a while” but I don’t have any shelves except my completed shelf. (A never-ending shelf makes me feel guilty if I never choose the books on it.) So I decided to do a re-read!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is one of the books in my 2012 span of using Goodreads (there’s a gap between 2012 &amp;#x26; 2015, which was me being a busy university student). I remember reading it earlier than that because it a was a shared favourite between me and one of my oldest bookworm buddies. We used to say “Owen!” and sigh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway! This book is about magic in New York City and how one Midwestern girl finds out about it due to her immunity to magical spells. &lt;em&gt;Enchanted, Inc.&lt;/em&gt; is the first book of her adventures with it, and there’s a cute and powerful wizard in it called Owen (hehe). It’s short and sweet and reminded me of many shared book moments with an old friend &amp;#x3C;3&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sag Harbor&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Goodreads Summer Reading Challenge: Sand Between My Toes&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This month’s challenge categories featured a lot of beachiness, but I didn’t want all fluffy reads. So I discovered &lt;em&gt;Sag Harbor&lt;/em&gt;, a book about “black boys with beach houses” in the mid-80s. It was an eye-opening read for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I never considered that people of colour were barred from owning a place in the Hamptons, but given history, it makes sense. So it was fun to dive into the culture, with the rap rhymes, the summer jobs, and the freedom of parents being in the city. All with the backdrop of being black of a certain privilege, including going to fancy private schools, but being the only black boys there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was younger, I enjoyed books from the point of boys, reading everything from &lt;em&gt;Captain Underpants&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;The Day My Butt Went Psycho&lt;/em&gt;, to the &lt;em&gt;Swim the Fly&lt;/em&gt; series by Don Calame. It was fun to see things from another perspective, and reading &lt;em&gt;Sag Harbor&lt;/em&gt; reminded me of this joy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mãn&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Goodreads Summer Reading Challenge: One and Done&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the benefits of reading fast is that what counts as a one-sitting read can be pretty long. &lt;em&gt;Mãn&lt;/em&gt; surprised me though! I chose it because it is a slim book, but it is full of depth and almost reads like free verse poetry. And one does not simply speed read poetry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You taste the words, and savour them, and &lt;em&gt;feel&lt;/em&gt; them. Which is perfect for this book, a tale that intertwines culture, immigration, and food. This is my second read by this author, and I loved this one even more than &lt;em&gt;Ru&lt;/em&gt; because of the descriptions of food. I love local authors!!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good thing I’m done my reviews for this week and can go eat some pho or banh mi now.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Reading Roundup 21]]></title><description><![CDATA[Another trip derailed me this week! My days were wonderfully full, and I got to discover a bit of the diverse city of Toronto (never…]]></description><link>https://voracious-bookworm.com/reading-roundup-21/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://voracious-bookworm.com/reading-roundup-21/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Another trip derailed me this week! My days were wonderfully full, and I got to discover a bit of the diverse city of Toronto (never pronounced with the second t) &amp;#x3C;3&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Back Talk&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Goodreads Summer Reading Challenge: Won’t Be Long&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sixteen powerful stories packed into one book! I was amazed at the variety in characters. I loved reading stories about women of all different ages, flaws and strengths. It was the perfect book to bring on a work trip because I could easily read one story in downtime and not lose context.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Reading Roundup 20]]></title><description><![CDATA[I completed my Goodreads challenge this week! 74 books because I thought I was only doing two reading challenges. If I’m being honest to…]]></description><link>https://voracious-bookworm.com/reading-roundup-20/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://voracious-bookworm.com/reading-roundup-20/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I completed my Goodreads challenge this week! 74 books because I thought I was only doing two reading challenges. If I’m being honest to myself though, I was probably still going to read more than that, hehe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Binti: Home&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Goodreads Summer Reading Challenge: Sun, Moon, and Stars&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes! I identified so much with Binti in this story, who is unique in so many of the roles she takes on. I never would have guessed that I would find this in a sci-fi book set in space. Then again, this series is unique. Even Ursula K. Le Guin said “There’s more vivid imagination in a page of Nnedi Okorafor’s work than in whole volumes of ordinary fantasy epics.” So go read this one while I wait for my hold on the third one to become available! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Binti: Night Masquerade&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Goodreads Summer Reading Challenge: The Future is Always Bright&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I ended up getting this book a few days later! The final book in the series, and I’m glad I was able to choose this book for this challenge because it mentioned the future setting in &lt;em&gt;Home&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sadly, this Binti book wasn’t my favourite, because there were just so many loose ends to tie together. That distinction goes to &lt;em&gt;Home&lt;/em&gt;. I wish there were more Binti books, instead of this messy, unsatisfying conclusion. Ah well, I can only hope to read more Nnedi Okafor in the future. ;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Naked Alliances&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Goodreads Summer Reading Challenge: I Feel a Breeze&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was a fun romp of a book! I must admit that I wasn’t sure I’d like it because I tend to pick things that lots of people have (generally good) opinions on. For this challenge though, there weren’t many options. And if I’ve learned something about me as a reader this year, it’s that I like fun mysteries. (Though I really shouldn’t be surprised about this given my reading choices of Encyclopedia Brown and Nancy Drew as a little girl).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Naked Alliances&lt;/em&gt; did require a certain amount of open-mindedness for its content, but I don’t think it would shock many people in my circles (mostly millennials in Montreal?), and the serious subjects felt more background to the action. It reminds me of reading &lt;em&gt;Peyton Place&lt;/em&gt; (a book that was banned in Canada), and feeling underwhelmed, then grateful that society has opened up about once taboo subjects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Paletas&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Goodreads Summer Reading Challenge: Get Your Grill On&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I chose this book because my original selection got renewed at the library and won’t make to me in time for this month. I’m glad it worked out though! I learned about a cool (pun intended, since paletas are ice pops) slice of Mexican cuisine that only makes me want to visit it even more. Also I like things that confirm that avocado can be dessert food (not just guac people!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Beauty Tips from Moose Jaw&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Goodreads Summer Reading Challenge: Forefathers&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book was a recommendation from my parents, who helped me visit almost all the provinces (but no territories!) in Canada. Thank you Mom &amp;#x26; Dad!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While it’s not directly about the founding fathers (my, how patriarchal), it does dive into several of the outposts that made Canada what it is today. And that my friends, is a lot more exciting than any of the books I found about our founding fathers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book makes me want to finally make a trip to Newfoundland, and do more road trips around the beautiful province I live in, and generally celebrate being Canadian &amp;#x3C;3 Oh, and it will probably make you laugh too :D&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Wedding Date&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Goodreads Summer Reading Challenge: Diversify Yourself&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh what a feel-good story! This is my kind of chick lit! Y’know the one where the woman of colour gets the guy? To be real though, how many chick flicks feature a woman of colour? There has to be better representation. Thankfully I can read books like this in the meantime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I loved the little details in this book that spoke to what it’s like to date a white guy as a woman of colour. “Am I going to be the only black person there?” &lt;em&gt;So&lt;/em&gt; relateable. It even covered the trials of long distance relationships and communicating through emotionless texts. So yes, this was the perfect cheesy read for me. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And please, as if I haven’t already read authors of colour (at least twenty, okay?). I’ll admit it does take effort though, but it’s well worth it.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Reading Roundup 19]]></title><description><![CDATA[I’ve been home for a week and my reading speed has returned! I blame it on the ridiculously hot weather that makes me want to stay still…]]></description><link>https://voracious-bookworm.com/reading-roundup-19/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://voracious-bookworm.com/reading-roundup-19/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been home for a week and my reading speed has returned! I blame it on the ridiculously hot weather that makes me want to stay still.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Seating Arrangements&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Goodreads Summer Reading Challenge: Backyard BBQ&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book read as painfully elitist. Perhaps that was the point of it? There were many POV changes that opened different storylines and by the end, I felt like not all of them were tied off. Or maybe I was disappointed that the one character I identified with (the non-white, not rich one) didn’t have a neat end to her story. Anyway! This book put me off WASPy stories so much that I started &lt;em&gt;The Vacationers&lt;/em&gt; by Emma Straub and I couldn’t get past the first few pages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Red-Haired Woman&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Goodreads Summer Reading Challenge: Red, White, and Blue&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I promise that I chose this book before I saw my dad’s collection of Orhan Pamuk books! Then again, I chose it because it had the word “Red” in the title. It doesn’t matter because this book was such a breath of fresh air after the cloying, WASPy &lt;em&gt;Seating Arrangements&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was enchanted by the new-to-me location (Turkey), the Eastern vibes, and I just flew through the story. That’s the magic of Nobel Prize winners right? It actually reminded me of &lt;em&gt;The Bad Girl&lt;/em&gt; by Mario Vargas Llosa for the way it followed one man’s life, and the threads of obsession throughout the story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time to sneak in some more Orhan Pamuk into my reading challenges!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fangirls&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Goodreads Summer Reading Challenge: Embrace Your Inner Geek&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best part of this book was the way it encourages and validates the fangirl experience. I also appreciated the way it addresses the toxic behaviours that can be in the community. While things are slowly getting better, I think it’s important to be ready for the shitty stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, I was confused at the target age group for this book. The tone sounded middle/high school but one section mentioned grabbing beers to make friends. It’s a great resource if you want a self-contained intro, but so much of it can be found online. Then again, I’m probably biased by my geeky computer background.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is Everyone Hanging Out Without Me?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Goodreads Summer Reading Challenge: Funny Bone&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love Mindy Kaling! It’s gratifying to read a famous funny woman of colour. This was a fun collection of essays on different things. I appreciate the random list-making! Also I’m &lt;em&gt;so&lt;/em&gt; glad her wish of Ocean’s 8 became a real thing. Go seeeeeee it, just for the badass women in it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In the Bag&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Goodreads Summer Reading Challenge: Beach Bum&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was in middle school, I read all the Kate Klise books I could, and my favourite one was the very summery &lt;em&gt;Letters From Camp&lt;/em&gt;. Kate Klise and her illustrator sister took the epistolary style to the next level, using notes, new headlines, maps, and other written ephemera to tell these stories. I was fascinated!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In the Bag&lt;/em&gt; is one of Klise’s adult novels, and still, letters (emails) were featured! It was a fun one-sitting read that had me girly-squealing from the unrealistic but too cute storyline. In other words, a perfect beach read.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;13 Ways to Look at a Fat Girl&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Goodreads Summer Reading Challenge: Colours of Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, so the cover is arguably green, but I hey, I wanted to read this Canadian author (especially since she was born in my city &amp;#x3C;3).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I seem to be on a roll with books that feature unhealthy obsession. This one was particularly sad to me, maybe because I know obsession with body fat/weight is so prevalent in our society and disproportionately affects women.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book dives into different times in main character’s life, so you get a thorough view on the many ways being fat, and maybe more importantly, feeling fat impacts her life. It made me equal parts sad and mad at society, and what better compliment to a book can you give than “it made me feel things”!?&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Reading Roundup 18]]></title><description><![CDATA[Goodbye vacation! It’s finally back to work time for me tomorrow but at least I managed to squeeze in two books in the past week. :) Perhaps…]]></description><link>https://voracious-bookworm.com/reading-roundup-18/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://voracious-bookworm.com/reading-roundup-18/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 08 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Goodbye vacation! It’s finally back to work time for me tomorrow but at least I managed to squeeze in two books in the past week. :) Perhaps my commute will mean more reading? (But more likely catching up on emails…)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Riders of the Purple Shade&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Goodreads Summer Reading Challenge: High Noon&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first I was dreading to read another western novel (I read &lt;em&gt;True Grit&lt;/em&gt; earlier this year for the Read Harder Challenge by Book Riot), but it was fitting that I read this book when I did - during &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.calgarystampede.com/&quot;&gt;Stampede&lt;/a&gt; season! It put me in the mood to see horses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book actually reminded me of &lt;em&gt;A Study in Scarlet&lt;/em&gt; for its harsh depiction of Mormons, though it was published 25 years after Sherlock’s tale. What I liked the most were the descriptions of the scenery (although maybe the purple sage was mentioned a tad too much), and the two interwoven storylines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It exceeded my expectations in readability for a book published in 1912! I loved imaging some of the accents of the characters. &lt;em&gt;The Sisters Brothers&lt;/em&gt; would still top my list for western recommendations, but this one would come up if someone were asking for more than one. :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Bad Girl&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Goodreads Summer Reading Challenge: You Have a Lovely Accent&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Psh, this was no challenge for me! I’ve already read several books in translation just this year (&lt;em&gt;Fever Dream&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;The Black City&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Midnight Sun&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Auntie Poldi and the Sicilian Lions&lt;/em&gt;). It must be a habit from watching foreign films with my parents. I’m grateful that so many books are translated into English.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was my third book by Mario Vargas Llosa, the Nobel Prize-winning author from Peru. I chose the first one (&lt;em&gt;In Praise of the Stepmother&lt;/em&gt;) right before my flight to South America, on the way to Peru, and finished it before we arrived. It was that good! So I had high expectations of &lt;em&gt;The Bad Girl&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn’t enjoy &lt;em&gt;The Bad Girl&lt;/em&gt; as much. I felt mostly felt bad for Ricardo, the main character, and frustrated with the object of his obsession, Otilia. Perhaps that’s the feeling Vargas Llosa was going for. The frustration of obsession.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, this one okay book won’t stop me from reading more Mario. There are still so many to try!&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Reading Roundup 17]]></title><description><![CDATA[Happy belated Canada Day! I’m immensely grateful to be Canadian 🇨🇦 I’ll have to compile a list of my fave Canadian authors someday. And…]]></description><link>https://voracious-bookworm.com/reading-roundup-17/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://voracious-bookworm.com/reading-roundup-17/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Happy belated Canada Day! I’m immensely grateful to be Canadian 🇨🇦 I’ll have to compile a list of my fave Canadian authors someday. And get to those Louise Penny books I’ve been meaning to read.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A River Runs Through It&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Goodreads Summer Reading Challenge: Hook ‘Em&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I considered a few books for this challenge (like &lt;em&gt;Trout Fishing in America&lt;/em&gt;) and got partway through &lt;em&gt;The History of Fly-Fishing in 50 Flies&lt;/em&gt; but &lt;em&gt;A River Runs Through It&lt;/em&gt; won out because it was at my parents’ house.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Growing up in a city with a couple big rivers and an outdoorsy vibe gave me opportunities to watch people fly-fishing. Trying to read the history book showed me how long the sport has been around. But this book was perfect for getting at why so many people love it. The descriptions of fishing have stayed in my head more than the sad family story woven into the scenery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So to me, this is more of a sit back, relax, and enjoy the meditative descriptions book. Almost like fly-fishing itself.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Reading Roundup 16]]></title><description><![CDATA[My reading has finally slowed down, unusually because of a vacation. It turns out that travelling with someone leaves me less time to read…]]></description><link>https://voracious-bookworm.com/reading-roundup-16/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://voracious-bookworm.com/reading-roundup-16/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;My reading has finally slowed down, unusually because of a vacation. It turns out that travelling with someone leaves me less time to read! On the other hand, I’ve been able to catch up with some of my oldest bookworm friends (like &lt;a href=&quot;https://livingintheinkworld.wordpress.com/&quot;&gt;Living in the Ink World&lt;/a&gt; 💝).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Year of Less&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Goodreads Summer Reading Challenge: TBRing It&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t have an official TBR (to-be-read) list but I saw this book in a few bookshelves earlier this year and had been meaning to read it, so that counts right? No one is keeping track anyway!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can’t remember what got me into personal finance, but I do remember being hooked on two Canadian personal finance reality shows: &lt;em&gt;Til Debt Do Us Part&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Princess&lt;/em&gt;. The host for both of them was the badass finance guru Gail Vaz-Oxlade, and she was in the business of financial makeovers. It was through these shows that I learned about budgets, the power of saving early, and just how awful consumer debt is. They also got me into reading more finance books and blogs, which eventually led me to this one too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My favourite finance books are the ones that aren’t just about investing or saving (the how) but about thinking about what you actually want (the why). It’s crazy how much less you need when you decide that you don’t need certain things (and I’m definitely speaking from a place of privilege here). &lt;em&gt;The Year of Less&lt;/em&gt; fits right into this kind of story. In fact, it was more of a “what I really need” story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, this book didn’t really speak to me. It was cool to have a Canadian millenial perspective on money things, but because of Gail’s shows, the blogs and books that I’ve read, I didn’t find the idea very novel. The book was mostly about the author’s struggles with mindless consumption and I didn’t identify with a lot of it. I guess I wasn’t expecting a story about shopping struggles. I had to admire the author’s candor though!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This would be a good book for people who have struggled with debt and spending and perhaps young women who are about to start earning more money, but for me, it wasn’t that interesting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fever Dream&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Goodreads Summer Reading Challenge: Campfire Story&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hate horror. I can barely handle thrillers. So you can probably guess that this challenge wasn’t my favourite. I ended up choosing this book from a “horror for scaredy-cats” listicle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This one featured a creepy child and unknown horrors, which are two of the scariest things. Thankfully this book was short and I didn’t have to suffer too much to complete it. I actually spent half the time figuring out what was happening in the present and in the past. Definitely a book for those who like atmospheric horror.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s to no more horror categories in my reading challenges - there are only so many for scaredy-cats like me.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Reading Roundup 15]]></title><description><![CDATA[Keeping up the pace this week despite being distracted by re-reading a couple of my cheesy old YA favourites from high school ( Just Listen…]]></description><link>https://voracious-bookworm.com/reading-roundup-15/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://voracious-bookworm.com/reading-roundup-15/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 17 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Keeping up the pace this week despite being distracted by re-reading a couple of my cheesy old YA favourites from high school (&lt;em&gt;Just Listen&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;This Lullaby&lt;/em&gt; by Sarah Dessen)!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Daughter of the Pirate King&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;#x26; &lt;strong&gt;Daughter of the Siren Queen&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Popsugar Reading Challenge: Set at sea&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Goodreads Summer Reading Challenge: Ocean Blue&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This pair of YA books were a delightful jaunt into the world of pirates and sirens. The might have been my favourites if I’d read them in high school, but alas, they were a bit repetitive and shallow for me now. As a recommendation for YA readers for strong women and adventure, definitely. Maybe even an easy beach read.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Joy Luck Club&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Goodreads Summer Reading Challenge: School’s Out for Summer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last time I read this book was about ten years ago. I’d like to find the essay I wrote about it. The power of re-reading is in the reflection of how you’ve changed, and I’m sure I’d gain some insight by reading my old opinions. (I wonder what kinds of insight I’ll have reading back on this blog!?)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The style of multiple viewpoints over time seems like a theme in the Asian women authors I’ve read (&lt;em&gt;That Summer in Provincetown&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Ru&lt;/em&gt;). I feel like I’m getting a “2-for-1” kind of deal in terms of perspective. In &lt;em&gt;The Joy Luck Club&lt;/em&gt;, it’s eight stories woven together beautifully. It definitely deserves more than one read because you probably missed how some of the stories were connected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Children of Men&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Goodreads Summer Reading Challenge: It’s the End of the World&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In general, apocalyptic novels aren’t my favourite. So for this challenge I took the chance to read the book that inspired a movie I enjoyed of the same name. It turns out that the movie was quite different that the book (but that’s not really a surprise, is it?). Many of the elements from the book are in the movie, but with different characters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m glad I read a woman author for this challenge. It was fascinating perspective on an infertile human race. The parts that described dolls as desperate substitutes for real babies felt so creepy and heartbreaking. I wouldn’t read it again, but I might recommend it and maybe try to read more PD James?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Sleeper and the Spindle&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Goodreads Summer Reading Challenge: My, What Big Teeth You Have&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sleeping Beauty was never my favourite princess or story, so I was &lt;em&gt;so&lt;/em&gt; happy with this retelling. Neil Gaiman hasn’t disappointed me yet. Neither has Chris Riddell, the illustrator. This book is so short you should just go read it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cadillac Cathedral&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Goodreads Summer Reading Challenge: Into the Great Wide Open&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps this book wasn’t exactly set in the wilderness but there were rebellious acts in the relative wilderness of rural BC. It felt true to the Tom Petty song. I enjoyed this departure from a big city setting! Also it featured characters in retirement, and satisfyingly active ones. The perfect contrasting perspectiv eafter reading too much YA this week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book reminded how much I love friend visits on ordinary days when you or they are in the midst of chores. That’s when you know you’re good friends. Why wait for an “event” to hang out? So it pleased me to read the same sentiments in &lt;em&gt;Cadillac Cathedral&lt;/em&gt;. The other fun part for me were the mentions of Finnish culture and names which I was able to share with dear Finnish friend (and fellow bookworm). We’re already planning a &lt;em&gt;seisova pöytä&lt;/em&gt; (a kind of food spread/buffet).&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Reading Roundup 14]]></title><description><![CDATA[Fact: when you read six books in a week, there’s less time for writing about them. This week I’ll attempt to leave more time for writing…]]></description><link>https://voracious-bookworm.com/reading-roundup-14/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://voracious-bookworm.com/reading-roundup-14/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Fact: when you read six books in a week, there’s less time for writing about them. This week I’ll attempt to leave more time for writing!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Attachments&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Goodreads Summer Reading Challenge: Dear Pen Pal&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of my favourite books in elementary school was &lt;em&gt;Letters from Camp&lt;/em&gt; by Kate Klise, which was told through letters, notes, newspaper clippings, and other clippings. I was enchanted with the fact that you could tell an entire story with snippets of communication. So I was excited for this challenge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Attachments&lt;/em&gt; was told through a mix of emails (it’s a kind of letter right!?), and a limited third-person point-of-view. It was cute but I spent a bit of time cringing at the stereotypical IT guy depiction. This book did &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; age well with its mentions of Y2K. On the other hand it was fun to consider romance before the time of ubiquitous smartphones. Also it was Rainbow Rowell’s first book, I can forgive her. Otherwise I’d skip this book unless you feel nostalgic for 90s communication?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Crossover&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Goodreads Summer Reading Challenge: Sports-a-holic&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was not expecting a kids basketball book to be poetry-as-prose… so &lt;em&gt;The Crossover&lt;/em&gt; was a pleasant surprise! It reminded me of writing my own attempts at basketball-themed poetry in grade school. It’s a small book but manages to delve into fathers, sibling rivalry, and some young angst. All in free verse mind you. I’m filing this under favourite basketball stories!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Meanwhile&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Goodreads Summer Reading Challenge: Childhood Reboot&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Choose-your-own-adventure comic book! What more do I need to say? I read this book with bae and we both enjoyed it thoroughly. Give yourself a chunk of time to read it though, as the many storylines may frustrate you. Puzzle-lovers, put this on your TBR! (Yes, I know the challenge says &lt;em&gt;novel&lt;/em&gt; but trust me, this book requires more thinking than many novels.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grief is the Thing with Feathers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Goodreads Summer Reading Challenge: Father Knows Best&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This one brought on the feels. I purposely read about death (&lt;em&gt;From Here to Eternity&lt;/em&gt;) instead of grief for the Popsugar Reading Challenge and yet here I am, reviewing a book about grief. Like &lt;em&gt;The Crossover&lt;/em&gt;, this book used the lyrical quality of poetry-as-prose to tug on your heartstrings. I promise I didn’t pick two poetry-as-prose books this week on purpose!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn’t quite get the role of the crow in the book, probably because the main character is a Ted Hughes scholar and I have not read any Ted Hughes. (I did force myself through &lt;em&gt;Ariel&lt;/em&gt; by Sylvia Plath earlier this year.) I admire crows because they are wonderfully smart birds, but given the crow’s role in sadness in this book, I’m not tempted to read any Ted Hughes right now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, the contrast of the young boys’ grief compared to the father’s grief made the father’s grief that much stronger for me. And to think, I haven’t yet experienced this level of grief before. This will be on my list to read or suggest when that inevitable grief strikes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A note on the challenge category: Where are all the good dads in literature!?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rubyfruit Jungle&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Goodreads Summer Reading Challenge: Take Pride&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book made me think of &lt;em&gt;Peyton Place&lt;/em&gt;, which was banned in Canada at some point, because it was considered to be too scandalous. I can imagine Rubyfruit Jungle was considered scandalous at its publication due to its depiction of lesbian relationships. I’m sure the fact that title turned out to be the description of female gentalia made it even more offensive to some people, hehe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was my second read that centered around women loving women (the other being &lt;em&gt;Landing&lt;/em&gt; by Emma Donoghue, which I loved!), but it wasn’t only about that. I appreciated that Molly stayed true to herself throughout the book, whether it was about going to university or film school in New York. The sexism she experienced from getting into a predominantly (completely) men’s field reminded me of parts of tech industry I’m in today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before doing book challenges I used to want to pick books out “on my own”, like a hipster. Now I’m glad to have book challenges push me and give me an opportunity to read classics or seminal works like &lt;em&gt;Rubyfruit Jungle&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;99 Bottles of OOP&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Popsugar Reading Challenge: A book with song lyrics in the title&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I filled this challenge by accident, as this book was required reading for a workshop I got to do through work. It was so perfectly apt though, as the examples in the book centered around the lyrics of &lt;em&gt;99 Bottles&lt;/em&gt;. Turns out you can learn a lot of from one song :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Phew! That was an intense week of reading. And I passed 50 books read this year!&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Reading Roundup 13]]></title><description><![CDATA[Apparently travelling with friends means ice cream, kayaking, board games but no reading time. Whatever! I got quality over quantity this…]]></description><link>https://voracious-bookworm.com/reading-roundup-13/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://voracious-bookworm.com/reading-roundup-13/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 04 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Apparently travelling with friends means ice cream, kayaking, board games but no reading time. Whatever! I got quality over quantity this week 💖&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dianagabaldon.com/books/outlander-series/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Outlander&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Popsugar Reading Challenge: A book about time travel&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OMG. I &lt;em&gt;loved&lt;/em&gt; this book. It had a strong woman protagonist, sexy accents, sexy scenes, details galore, …
and more things that I can’t name because I’m so excited about the book!!!
I read this beautiful brick in two days! (I didn’t really know I was signing up for 600+ pages since I read the ebook version.)
It’s my first adult time-travelling book (I was going to say first overall, but then I remembered
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mollymoonsworld.com/the-books/molly-moon-books/&quot;&gt;Molly Moon&lt;/a&gt;) and I have to say I was skeptical that I would like it.
But ohhhh yes, I was proven wrong, very wrong. Reading until 4am to finish it wrong. Sometimes it’s unhealthy to be proven wrong. 😕&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s funny because while thinking about what I would write for this post, I realized how similiar it is to another one of my favourites: &lt;em&gt;Ransom My Heart&lt;/em&gt; by Meg Cabot.
I wonder how much of it was inspired by Outlander. Or maybe this is how most romances of this type are written.
Again, I thank my reading challenges for helping me try new reads!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, when I started raving about it to my fellow bookworms, they’d already read it (and the rest of the series!) and loved it. So you probably have as well.
But I don’t care that I’m late, I’m glad I discovered it!
And apparently the TV adaptation is great too (not that I’m going to watch it).
So if you haven’t already, go forth and experience it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://matthewquickwriter.com/novels/the-silver-linings-playbook/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Silver Linings Playbook&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Popsugar Reading Challenge: A book about mental health&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I’m extremely picky about which movies I watch, I often miss out on pop culture things. I can often fix that by reading the book
(which is usually the original anyway).
I did that with &lt;em&gt;Hidden Figures&lt;/em&gt; last year, and I’ll probably skip seeing &lt;em&gt;Crazy, Rich Asians&lt;/em&gt; since I already read and loved the book.
&lt;em&gt;The Silver Linings Playbook&lt;/em&gt; is the first book that’s made me want to see the movie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This novel is written from the first-person perspective of a person who has a mental illness.
I found this point-of-view to be refreshing, since you could see the struggle from the inside.
There were moments that made me laugh, but also many that broke my heart.
What I want to see is how they portrayed things from the outside in the movie (or did they?).
So while I do that, you can go and read that book :)&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Reading Roundup 12]]></title><description><![CDATA[I missed writing book reactions! Also I bumped into  Heather O’Neill  and I felt inspired to write more.
So here I am, back to writing about…]]></description><link>https://voracious-bookworm.com/reading-roundup-12/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://voracious-bookworm.com/reading-roundup-12/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 27 May 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I missed writing book reactions! Also I bumped into &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/lethal_heroine&quot;&gt;Heather O’Neill&lt;/a&gt; and I felt inspired to write more.
So here I am, back to writing about my week’s reads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://jessieannfoley.com/?page_id=47&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Carnival at Bray&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Popsugar Reading Challenge: A book set in the decade you were born&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was a fun read! It probably would have been one of my favourites if it had been released when I was in high school.
I’m a sucker for first love stories. Also I’ve been meaning to plan a trip to Ireland, and this book only fuels this wish even more.
The only question I’m left with now is how to pronounce Eoin. Oh Irish names &amp;#x3C;3&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Update: Apparently Eoin is like Owen 😍&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://heathbrothers.com/books/decisive/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Decisive: How to Make Better Choices in Life and Work&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Popsugar Reading Challenge: A book by two authors&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book was highly touted at work (and there were free copies to take), so I gave it a read.
There were plenty of actionable ideas in it, and quite applicable given that we all have thousands of decisions to make every day.
As someone who can get overwhelmed with the packed nature of non-fiction, I appreciated the chapter summaries.
Not the most enjoyable read of the week, but definitely useful and recommendable!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.simongarfield.com/pages/books/just_my_type.htm&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Just My Type: A Book About Fonts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Popsugar Reading Challenge: A microhistory&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I thought I was picky about fonts before… it’s much worse now. I loved this mish-mash of stories about type.
It put real humans behind the letters everyone sees! I was reminded of researching the mathematicians behind different formulas.
(Or maybe of a different microhistory I’ve read.) This book introduced me to the &lt;em&gt;world&lt;/em&gt; of type. It’s huge!
Thankfully we’re in the age of the Internet where I can simply search them online, not laboriously in doorstopper book.
I learned about the hate for Comic Sans and Arial, but also the love for Helvetica, and just how old some types are.
It even helped me choose the fonts for this new site (I ditched one because of its long commas).
So if you want to have a taste of the passion behind the shapes of letters, please read this book :)&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Hello World!]]></title><description><![CDATA[Exciting news!!! My book blog has a new home!
It even has a grown-up domain name (grown-up because I have to pay for it). Now that things…]]></description><link>https://voracious-bookworm.com/hello-world/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://voracious-bookworm.com/hello-world/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 24 May 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Exciting news!!! My book blog has a new home!
It even has a grown-up domain name (grown-up because I have to pay for it).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that things are setup, I’m looking forward to writing more.
Even more so that it’ll be in my favourite (arguably archaic) text-editor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, here’s a cat I met today! 🏀&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a
    class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-link&quot;
    href=&quot;/static/cat-020e4aa7314b54c1132ff1bcab5833ca-11eb7.jpg&quot;
    style=&quot;display: block&quot;
    target=&quot;_blank&quot;
    rel=&quot;noopener&quot;
  &gt;
  
  &lt;span
    class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-wrapper&quot;
    style=&quot;position: relative; display: block; ; max-width: 590px; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&quot;
  &gt;
    &lt;span
      class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-background-image&quot;
      style=&quot;padding-bottom: 100%; position: relative; bottom: 0; left: 0; background-image: url(&apos;data:image/jpeg;base64,/9j/2wBDABALDA4MChAODQ4SERATGCgaGBYWGDEjJR0oOjM9PDkzODdASFxOQERXRTc4UG1RV19iZ2hnPk1xeXBkeFxlZ2P/2wBDARESEhgVGC8aGi9jQjhCY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2P/wgARCAAUABQDASIAAhEBAxEB/8QAGAABAQEBAQAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAUDAgT/xAAWAQEBAQAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAABAAL/2gAMAwEAAhADEAAAAaU7uK597BVvA0Zgf//EABsQAAICAwEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAECAAMEEBEU/9oACAEBAAEFAjyW5KpPYZbWzl0ItOOdOO6//8QAFxEBAAMAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAEQIf/aAAgBAwEBPwFiK//EABgRAAIDAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAARARAh/9oACAECAQE/AWjSa//EABwQAAICAgMAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAABEBEhMgIiUf/aAAgBAQAGPwLBXHszVGGyqNlCfkf/xAAdEAACAgMAAwAAAAAAAAAAAAABEQAhEDFBUZHR/9oACAEBAAE/IVfUK1dboTy+8x1WTT2YZGhJnGXAwLsqx//aAAwDAQACAAMAAAAQX/8AvP/EABkRAQACAwAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAEAEBEhMf/aAAgBAwEBPxAB3MR1X//EABkRAAIDAQAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAABEBEhMf/aAAgBAgEBPxBtgs8R/8QAHRABAAIBBQEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAQARITFBUXGBYf/aAAgBAQABPxCw5YMuyVVFqKe271AzBfkqD2RdQJ5FnABxbBppGVEzHjaBjfRESf/Z&apos;); background-size: cover; display: block;&quot;
    &gt;
      &lt;img
        class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-image&quot;
        style=&quot;width: 100%; height: 100%; margin: 0; vertical-align: middle; position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; box-shadow: inset 0px 0px 0px 400px white;&quot;
        alt=&quot;Cat&quot;
        title=&quot;&quot;
        src=&quot;/static/cat-020e4aa7314b54c1132ff1bcab5833ca-f8fb9.jpg&quot;
        srcset=&quot;/static/cat-020e4aa7314b54c1132ff1bcab5833ca-e8976.jpg 148w,
/static/cat-020e4aa7314b54c1132ff1bcab5833ca-63df2.jpg 295w,
/static/cat-020e4aa7314b54c1132ff1bcab5833ca-f8fb9.jpg 590w,
/static/cat-020e4aa7314b54c1132ff1bcab5833ca-85e3d.jpg 885w,
/static/cat-020e4aa7314b54c1132ff1bcab5833ca-d1924.jpg 1180w,
/static/cat-020e4aa7314b54c1132ff1bcab5833ca-9452e.jpg 1770w,
/static/cat-020e4aa7314b54c1132ff1bcab5833ca-11eb7.jpg 3036w&quot;
        sizes=&quot;(max-width: 590px) 100vw, 590px&quot;
      /&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
  
  &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Reading Roundup 11]]></title><description><![CDATA[I’m done the 2018 Read Harder Challenge! It took me 71 days, so a book almost every three days.
That means I finished two months earlier…]]></description><link>https://voracious-bookworm.com/reading-roundup-11/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://voracious-bookworm.com/reading-roundup-11/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I’m done the 2018 Read Harder Challenge! It took me 71 days, so a book almost every three days.
That means I finished two months earlier than last year, and I am free to go on to the next challenge!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Lover&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Read Harder Challenge: A book of genre fiction in translation (romance)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book reminded me of &lt;em&gt;That Summer in Provincetown&lt;/em&gt;
(which is fitting, because that was the first read of the Read Harder Challenge, and this is my last read of it!!!)
in the vignette-style, the re-telling of the same events in different ways, and the setting in Southeast Asia.
I thought this one was less successful though. Perhaps because this one is fancier (it won the &lt;em&gt;Prix Goncourt&lt;/em&gt;).
Or maybe because it went over my head? It could just be literature that I am unequipped to examine. The story is sad but not surprising.
I completely understand why the content was controversial. Maybe that’s why people read it. Y’all can find out for yourselves. :)&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Reading Roundup 10]]></title><description><![CDATA[This week’s verdict: travel is excellent for my reading progress! It was fun to be in a cold country, yet reading about sweating in the hot…]]></description><link>https://voracious-bookworm.com/reading-roundup-10/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://voracious-bookworm.com/reading-roundup-10/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;This week’s verdict: travel is excellent for my reading progress! It was fun to be in a cold country, yet reading about sweating in the hot, Sicilian sun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Open House&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Read Harder Challenge: An Oprah Book Club selection&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of the Oprah Book Club selections looked like intensely emotional reads, and this one wasn’t an exception. I think I was able to stomach it because I’ve never gone through a divorce, but oh, how I felt the hurt in this one! But also the growth! The heart-wrenching, cringey beginning made the character development way more satisfying. It was definitely an inner conflict kind of book, the grown-up version to my favourite kinds of books as a teenager. This is the best part about reading - the lives you get to live without really living them (or maybe the worst part!?).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Auntie Poldi and the Sicilian Lions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Read Harder Challenge: A book with a female protagonist over the age of 60&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went on a Miss Marple-esque (older women detectives) streak! I read a Miss Marple short, then the first Aunty Lee, and then this lovely tale. It’s funny that I ended up reading this story right after Aunty Lee’s Delights because there are many similarities - the age of the investigators, the digressions on food, and the hot, humid settings (Singapore and Sicily - another similarity!). While I enjoyed both books, this one satisfied my mystery critic much better. It all came full circle! :D&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book makes me want to visit Sicily, go mushroom-picking, listen to elders argue about food, sit on the beach, drink great wine, and be passionate in general. That’s what it inspired in me, which is funny, because usually mysteries are all about the characters. And yes, the characters in the book are great! That’s why I mentioned listening to arguments and being passionate. But the descriptions of Italy were mouth-watering. Lit, as the cool people would say? So go read this book unless you want to avoid wanting to go to Italy. :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(P.S. This one was originally my choice for “A book of genre fiction in translation”, but it was much easier to find more genre fiction in translation than books with female protagonists over the age of 60 :()&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aunty Lee’s Delights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Read Harder Challenge: A mystery by a person of color or LGBTQ+ author&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I’m to be honest here, I might have chosen this novel because I had such a fun time reading a Singaporean series (&lt;em&gt;Crazy, Rich Asians&lt;/em&gt;) last year. What convinced me even more was that it was endorsed by Louise Penny, the popular Canadian mystery author (who I have yet to read, please forgive me). I found out in the notes at the end of the book that Ovidia Yu actually was inspired to write the novel because of Louise Penny! Ahh, the connections!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book was an enjoyable read. I loved the array of characters: unlikely investigator and chef Aunty Lee, her ever-helpful, Watson-like Filipina maid, the social-climbing daughter-in-law that reminded me of &lt;em&gt;Crazy, Rich Asians&lt;/em&gt; series, and so many more. I loved that Aunty Lee’s superpower is her cooking, and that food elements are weaved throughout the whole book. It’s even mentioned that her notes are reminiscent of a recipe :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a treat to read a mystery featuring people of colour. I guess I’ve been reading a lot of old-school mysteries set in Britain or Europe. Thank you Read Harder Challenge for making me discover other delights!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wasn’t a huge fan of how the investigation finished. It felt like many of the details came out at the end, and I find that the most satisfying mysteries are those that tie up clues from the beginning. Or maybe my expectations are at peak Agatha Christie level ;) Even so, I had fun reading this story, and I look forward to reading the rest of the series!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(P.S. I originally set out to read &lt;em&gt;The Summer We Got Free&lt;/em&gt; by Mia McKenzie since it’s written by a badass PoC and LGBTQ+ but it was unavailable at the three library systems I have access to!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;True Grit&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Read Harder Challenge: A western&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had to choose this book when I realized that main character is a young woman seeking to avenge her father. How many westerns feature that!? I wouldn’t actually know because I don’t read or watch a lot of westerns. I do know that revenge, outlaws, gold, and horses are common threads though, and this book has ‘em all!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While it was fun to have a woman lead, I did enjoy &lt;em&gt;The Sisters Brothers&lt;/em&gt; more than this book. I remember laughing more. And I hated the description of the amputation… Maybe I shouldn’t watch the movie then. A version of &lt;em&gt;The Sisters Brothers&lt;/em&gt; is due to come out this year though! So I’d say if you wanna dip your toes into a western, this ain’t bad but I liked &lt;em&gt;The Sisters Brothers&lt;/em&gt; better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;July’s People&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Read Harder Challenge: A book set in or about one of the five BRICS countries (Brazil, Russia, India, China, or South Africa)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I chose this book because it’s by Nadine Gordimer, a South African winner of the Nobel Prize in Literature. I love crossing off two challenge requirements with one book! It also makes choosing books easier &amp;#x3C;3 I actually chose &lt;em&gt;No Time Like the Present&lt;/em&gt; first, which is also by Gordimer, but I found it the writing style hard to follow. Maybe if I’d read it during my travels I might have tried harder to get through it ;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This novel was one vision Gordimer had of the end of apartheid in South Africa, about a decade before it happened, where a civil war caused a white family to flee into hiding in their black employee’s village. I’m not familiar with a lot of this part of history, so I ended up reading more on South Africa to give myself more context for the read. Yay for books that expand our horizons!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book only told the the story of one family, but this was so powerful, because you can feel the growing helplessness of the parents. I found it quite accurate that the kids in the family easily adjusted, picking up the customs, the language, and of course, playmates. While I can’t say that I enjoyed reading this book since the topics were quite heavy, but I’m glad I did because it allowed me to learn more about another corner of our planet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Old Chief Mshlanga&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Read Harder Challenge: A book of colonial or postcolonial literature&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I chose this little story to introduce myself to Doris Lessing, another Nobel Prize-winning woman, and I wasn’t disappointed. In a small amount of text she was able to dive into colonial tensions without naming specific places. I also got another coming-of-age story, which I loved in this case, because the girl’s realization of injustice feels more emotional. I think I’ll have to pick up more Doris Lessing!&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Reading Roundup 9]]></title><description><![CDATA[Week 9 features only one book, a much denser non-fiction story. It often takes me longer to read non-fiction, and this one was no exception…]]></description><link>https://voracious-bookworm.com/reading-roundup-9/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://voracious-bookworm.com/reading-roundup-9/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Week 9 features only one book, a much denser non-fiction story. It often takes me longer to read non-fiction, and this one was no exception.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Soul of a New Machine&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Read Harder Challenge: An assigned book you never finished&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book was assigned for a bonus mark on the final exam in my computer systems class. I’d say that the five core courses I was taking that semester (my first in Computer Science) got in the way of reading it. I don’t think I would have appreciated it as much back then! My mom would say it’s because I’ve gotten nerdier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book was an adventure into the development of a new computer. It made me appreciate how far we’ve come in technology, and glad that working in computers doesn’t require the crazy dedication described in the book (though there are definitely people in tech who still work that much!). I loved finding out about Betty Shanahan, the one woman on the team, the references to Adventure, an early text adventure game (if you’ve never tried one, please do!!!), and clever analogies by Terry Pratchett. Basically, it pleased the nerd in me (the computer one, not the bio one).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re worried that it’s too nerdy for you though, remember that it won a Pulitzer Prize, and that’s for a good reason: you’re kept on the edge of your seat, and the technical details are explained in an approachable way. It got me inspired for my own teaching - earlier this year, I had to explain some of the concepts mentioned in the book to my students. I guess now I know why it was assigned ;)&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>