<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Voracious Bookworm]]></title><description><![CDATA[writings about devoured books]]></description><link>https://voracious-bookworm.com</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2018 02:03:44 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[Reading Roundup 13]]></title><description><![CDATA[Apparently travelling with friends means ice cream, kayaking, board games but no reading time. Whatever! I got quality over quantity this…]]></description><link>https://voracious-bookworm.com/reading-roundup-13/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://voracious-bookworm.com/reading-roundup-13/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 04 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Apparently travelling with friends means ice cream, kayaking, board games but no reading time. Whatever! I got quality over quantity this week 💖&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dianagabaldon.com/books/outlander-series/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Outlander&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Popsugar Reading Challenge: A book about time travel&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OMG. I &lt;em&gt;loved&lt;/em&gt; this book. It had a strong woman protagonist, sexy accents, sexy scenes, details galore, …
and more things that I can’t name because I’m so excited about the book!!!
I read this beautiful brick in two days! (I didn’t really know I was signing up for 600+ pages since I read the ebook version.)
It’s my first adult time-travelling book (I was going to say first overall, but then I remembered
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mollymoonsworld.com/the-books/molly-moon-books/&quot;&gt;Molly Moon&lt;/a&gt;) and I have to say I was skeptical that I would like it.
But ohhhh yes, I was proven wrong, very wrong. Reading until 4am to finish it wrong. Sometimes it’s unhealthy to be proven wrong. 😕&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s funny because while thinking about what I would write for this post, I realized how similiar it is to another one of my favourites: &lt;em&gt;Ransom My Heart&lt;/em&gt; by Meg Cabot.
I wonder how much of it was inspired by Outlander. Or maybe this is how most romances of this type are written.
Again, I thank my reading challenges for helping me try new reads!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, when I started raving about it to my fellow bookworms, they’d already read it (and the rest of the series!) and loved it. So you probably have as well.
But I don’t care that I’m late, I’m glad I discovered it!
And apparently the TV adaptation is great too (not that I’m going to watch it).
So if you haven’t already, go forth and experience it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://matthewquickwriter.com/novels/the-silver-linings-playbook/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Silver Linings Playbook&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Popsugar Reading Challenge: A book about mental health&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I’m extremely picky about which movies I watch, I often miss out on pop culture things. I can often fix that by reading the book
(which is usually the original anyway).
I did that with &lt;em&gt;Hidden Figures&lt;/em&gt; last year, and I’ll probably skip seeing &lt;em&gt;Crazy, Rich Asians&lt;/em&gt; since I already read and loved the book.
&lt;em&gt;The Silver Linings Playbook&lt;/em&gt; is the first book that’s made me want to see the movie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This novel is written from the first-person perspective of a person who has a mental illness.
I found this point-of-view to be refreshing, since you could see the struggle from the inside.
There were moments that made me laugh, but also many that broke my heart.
What I want to see is how they portrayed things from the outside in the movie (or did they?).
So while I do that, you can go and read that book :)&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Reading Roundup 12]]></title><description><![CDATA[I missed writing book reactions! Also I bumped into  Heather O’Neill  and I felt inspired to write more.
So here I am, back to writing about…]]></description><link>https://voracious-bookworm.com/reading-roundup-12/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://voracious-bookworm.com/reading-roundup-12/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 27 May 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I missed writing book reactions! Also I bumped into &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/lethal_heroine&quot;&gt;Heather O’Neill&lt;/a&gt; and I felt inspired to write more.
So here I am, back to writing about my week’s reads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://jessieannfoley.com/?page_id=47&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Carnival at Bray&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Popsugar Reading Challenge: A book set in the decade you were born&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was a fun read! It probably would have been one of my favourites if it had been released when I was in high school.
I’m a sucker for first love stories. Also I’ve been meaning to plan a trip to Ireland, and this book only fuels this wish even more.
The only question I’m left with now is how to pronounce Eoin. Oh Irish names &amp;#x3C;3&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Update: Apparently Eoin is like Owen 😍&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://heathbrothers.com/books/decisive/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Decisive: How to Make Better Choices in Life and Work&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Popsugar Reading Challenge: A book by two authors&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book was highly touted at work (and there were free copies to take), so I gave it a read.
There were plenty of actionable ideas in it, and quite applicable given that we all have thousands of decisions to make every day.
As someone who can get overwhelmed with the packed nature of non-fiction, I appreciated the chapter summaries.
Not the most enjoyable read of the week, but definitely useful and recommendable!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.simongarfield.com/pages/books/just_my_type.htm&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Just My Type: A Book About Fonts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Popsugar Reading Challenge: A microhistory&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I thought I was picky about fonts before… it’s much worse now. I loved this mish-mash of stories about type.
It put real humans behind the letters everyone sees! I was reminded of researching the mathematicians behind different formulas.
(Or maybe of a different microhistory I’ve read.) This book introduced me to the &lt;em&gt;world&lt;/em&gt; of type. It’s huge!
Thankfully we’re in the age of the Internet where I can simply search them online, not laboriously in doorstopper book.
I learned about the hate for Comic Sans and Arial, but also the love for Helvetica, and just how old some types are.
It even helped me choose the fonts for this new site (I ditched one because of its long commas).
So if you want to have a taste of the passion behind the shapes of letters, please read this book :)&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Hello World!]]></title><description><![CDATA[Exciting news!!! My book blog has a new home!
It even has a grown-up domain name (grown-up because I have to pay for it). Now that things…]]></description><link>https://voracious-bookworm.com/hello-world/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://voracious-bookworm.com/hello-world/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 24 May 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Exciting news!!! My book blog has a new home!
It even has a grown-up domain name (grown-up because I have to pay for it).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that things are setup, I’m looking forward to writing more.
Even more so that it’ll be in my favourite (arguably archaic) text-editor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, here’s a cat I met today! 🏀&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a
    class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-link&quot;
    href=&quot;/static/cat-020e4aa7314b54c1132ff1bcab5833ca-11eb7.jpg&quot;
    style=&quot;display: block&quot;
    target=&quot;_blank&quot;
    rel=&quot;noopener&quot;
  &gt;
  
  &lt;span
    class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-wrapper&quot;
    style=&quot;position: relative; display: block; ; max-width: 590px; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&quot;
  &gt;
    &lt;span
      class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-background-image&quot;
      style=&quot;padding-bottom: 100%; position: relative; bottom: 0; left: 0; background-image: url(&apos;data:image/jpeg;base64,/9j/2wBDABALDA4MChAODQ4SERATGCgaGBYWGDEjJR0oOjM9PDkzODdASFxOQERXRTc4UG1RV19iZ2hnPk1xeXBkeFxlZ2P/2wBDARESEhgVGC8aGi9jQjhCY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2P/wgARCAAUABQDASIAAhEBAxEB/8QAGAABAQEBAQAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAUDAgT/xAAWAQEBAQAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAABAAL/2gAMAwEAAhADEAAAAaU7uK597BVvA0Zgf//EABsQAAICAwEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAECAAMEEBEU/9oACAEBAAEFAjyW5KpPYZbWzl0ItOOdOO6//8QAFxEBAAMAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAEQIf/aAAgBAwEBPwFiK//EABgRAAIDAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAARARAh/9oACAECAQE/AWjSa//EABwQAAICAgMAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAABEBEhMgIiUf/aAAgBAQAGPwLBXHszVGGyqNlCfkf/xAAdEAACAgMAAwAAAAAAAAAAAAABEQAhEDFBUZHR/9oACAEBAAE/IVfUK1dboTy+8x1WTT2YZGhJnGXAwLsqx//aAAwDAQACAAMAAAAQX/8AvP/EABkRAQACAwAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAEAEBEhMf/aAAgBAwEBPxAB3MR1X//EABkRAAIDAQAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAABEBEhMf/aAAgBAgEBPxBtgs8R/8QAHRABAAIBBQEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAQARITFBUXGBYf/aAAgBAQABPxCw5YMuyVVFqKe271AzBfkqD2RdQJ5FnABxbBppGVEzHjaBjfRESf/Z&apos;); background-size: cover; display: block;&quot;
    &gt;
      &lt;img
        class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-image&quot;
        style=&quot;width: 100%; height: 100%; margin: 0; vertical-align: middle; position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; box-shadow: inset 0px 0px 0px 400px white;&quot;
        alt=&quot;Cat&quot;
        title=&quot;&quot;
        src=&quot;/static/cat-020e4aa7314b54c1132ff1bcab5833ca-f8fb9.jpg&quot;
        srcset=&quot;/static/cat-020e4aa7314b54c1132ff1bcab5833ca-e8976.jpg 148w,
/static/cat-020e4aa7314b54c1132ff1bcab5833ca-63df2.jpg 295w,
/static/cat-020e4aa7314b54c1132ff1bcab5833ca-f8fb9.jpg 590w,
/static/cat-020e4aa7314b54c1132ff1bcab5833ca-85e3d.jpg 885w,
/static/cat-020e4aa7314b54c1132ff1bcab5833ca-d1924.jpg 1180w,
/static/cat-020e4aa7314b54c1132ff1bcab5833ca-9452e.jpg 1770w,
/static/cat-020e4aa7314b54c1132ff1bcab5833ca-11eb7.jpg 3036w&quot;
        sizes=&quot;(max-width: 590px) 100vw, 590px&quot;
      /&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
  
  &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Reading Roundup 11]]></title><description><![CDATA[I’m done the 2018 Read Harder Challenge! It took me 71 days, so a book almost every three days.
That means I finished two months earlier…]]></description><link>https://voracious-bookworm.com/reading-roundup-11/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://voracious-bookworm.com/reading-roundup-11/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I’m done the 2018 Read Harder Challenge! It took me 71 days, so a book almost every three days.
That means I finished two months earlier than last year, and I am free to go on to the next challenge!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Lover&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Read Harder Challenge: A book of genre fiction in translation (romance)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book reminded me of &lt;em&gt;That Summer in Provincetown&lt;/em&gt;
(which is fitting, because that was the first read of the Read Harder Challenge, and this is my last read of it!!!)
in the vignette-style, the re-telling of the same events in different ways, and the setting in Southeast Asia.
I thought this one was less successful though. Perhaps because this one is fancier (it won the &lt;em&gt;Prix Goncourt&lt;/em&gt;).
Or maybe because it went over my head? It could just be literature that I am unequipped to examine. The story is sad but not surprising.
I completely understand why the content was controversial. Maybe that’s why people read it. Y’all can find out for yourselves. :)&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Reading Roundup 10]]></title><description><![CDATA[This week’s verdict: travel is excellent for my reading progress! It was fun to be in a cold country, yet reading about sweating in the hot…]]></description><link>https://voracious-bookworm.com/reading-roundup-10/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://voracious-bookworm.com/reading-roundup-10/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;This week’s verdict: travel is excellent for my reading progress! It was fun to be in a cold country, yet reading about sweating in the hot, Sicilian sun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Open House&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Read Harder Challenge: An Oprah Book Club selection&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of the Oprah Book Club selections looked like intensely emotional reads, and this one wasn’t an exception. I think I was able to stomach it because I’ve never gone through a divorce, but oh, how I felt the hurt in this one! But also the growth! The heart-wrenching, cringey beginning made the character development way more satisfying. It was definitely an inner conflict kind of book, the grown-up version to my favourite kinds of books as a teenager. This is the best part about reading - the lives you get to live without really living them (or maybe the worst part!?).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Auntie Poldi and the Sicilian Lions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Read Harder Challenge: A book with a female protagonist over the age of 60&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went on a Miss Marple-esque (older women detectives) streak! I read a Miss Marple short, then the first Aunty Lee, and then this lovely tale. It’s funny that I ended up reading this story right after Aunty Lee’s Delights because there are many similarities - the age of the investigators, the digressions on food, and the hot, humid settings (Singapore and Sicily - another similarity!). While I enjoyed both books, this one satisfied my mystery critic much better. It all came full circle! :D&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book makes me want to visit Sicily, go mushroom-picking, listen to elders argue about food, sit on the beach, drink great wine, and be passionate in general. That’s what it inspired in me, which is funny, because usually mysteries are all about the characters. And yes, the characters in the book are great! That’s why I mentioned listening to arguments and being passionate. But the descriptions of Italy were mouth-watering. Lit, as the cool people would say? So go read this book unless you want to avoid wanting to go to Italy. :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(P.S. This one was originally my choice for “A book of genre fiction in translation”, but it was much easier to find more genre fiction in translation than books with female protagonists over the age of 60 :()&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aunty Lee’s Delights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Read Harder Challenge: A mystery by a person of color or LGBTQ+ author&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I’m to be honest here, I might have chosen this novel because I had such a fun time reading a Singaporean series (&lt;em&gt;Crazy, Rich Asians&lt;/em&gt;) last year. What convinced me even more was that it was endorsed by Louise Penny, the popular Canadian mystery author (who I have yet to read, please forgive me). I found out in the notes at the end of the book that Ovidia Yu actually was inspired to write the novel because of Louise Penny! Ahh, the connections!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book was an enjoyable read. I loved the array of characters: unlikely investigator and chef Aunty Lee, her ever-helpful, Watson-like Filipina maid, the social-climbing daughter-in-law that reminded me of &lt;em&gt;Crazy, Rich Asians&lt;/em&gt; series, and so many more. I loved that Aunty Lee’s superpower is her cooking, and that food elements are weaved throughout the whole book. It’s even mentioned that her notes are reminiscent of a recipe :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a treat to read a mystery featuring people of colour. I guess I’ve been reading a lot of old-school mysteries set in Britain or Europe. Thank you Read Harder Challenge for making me discover other delights!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wasn’t a huge fan of how the investigation finished. It felt like many of the details came out at the end, and I find that the most satisfying mysteries are those that tie up clues from the beginning. Or maybe my expectations are at peak Agatha Christie level ;) Even so, I had fun reading this story, and I look forward to reading the rest of the series!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(P.S. I originally set out to read &lt;em&gt;The Summer We Got Free&lt;/em&gt; by Mia McKenzie since it’s written by a badass PoC and LGBTQ+ but it was unavailable at the three library systems I have access to!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;True Grit&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Read Harder Challenge: A western&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had to choose this book when I realized that main character is a young woman seeking to avenge her father. How many westerns feature that!? I wouldn’t actually know because I don’t read or watch a lot of westerns. I do know that revenge, outlaws, gold, and horses are common threads though, and this book has ‘em all!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While it was fun to have a woman lead, I did enjoy &lt;em&gt;The Sisters Brothers&lt;/em&gt; more than this book. I remember laughing more. And I hated the description of the amputation… Maybe I shouldn’t watch the movie then. A version of &lt;em&gt;The Sisters Brothers&lt;/em&gt; is due to come out this year though! So I’d say if you wanna dip your toes into a western, this ain’t bad but I liked &lt;em&gt;The Sisters Brothers&lt;/em&gt; better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;July’s People&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Read Harder Challenge: A book set in or about one of the five BRICS countries (Brazil, Russia, India, China, or South Africa)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I chose this book because it’s by Nadine Gordimer, a South African winner of the Nobel Prize in Literature. I love crossing off two challenge requirements with one book! It also makes choosing books easier &amp;#x3C;3 I actually chose &lt;em&gt;No Time Like the Present&lt;/em&gt; first, which is also by Gordimer, but I found it the writing style hard to follow. Maybe if I’d read it during my travels I might have tried harder to get through it ;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This novel was one vision Gordimer had of the end of apartheid in South Africa, about a decade before it happened, where a civil war caused a white family to flee into hiding in their black employee’s village. I’m not familiar with a lot of this part of history, so I ended up reading more on South Africa to give myself more context for the read. Yay for books that expand our horizons!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book only told the the story of one family, but this was so powerful, because you can feel the growing helplessness of the parents. I found it quite accurate that the kids in the family easily adjusted, picking up the customs, the language, and of course, playmates. While I can’t say that I enjoyed reading this book since the topics were quite heavy, but I’m glad I did because it allowed me to learn more about another corner of our planet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Old Chief Mshlanga&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Read Harder Challenge: A book of colonial or postcolonial literature&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I chose this little story to introduce myself to Doris Lessing, another Nobel Prize-winning woman, and I wasn’t disappointed. In a small amount of text she was able to dive into colonial tensions without naming specific places. I also got another coming-of-age story, which I loved in this case, because the girl’s realization of injustice feels more emotional. I think I’ll have to pick up more Doris Lessing!&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>